it was the worst professional experience
那是
of my career and this was before the me
我职业生涯中最糟糕的经历，而且这还是在
too movement I felt humiliated and
#MeToo运动之前。我感到羞辱和人格
degraded what can you say about that
贬低。你能说说那段
experience Rebel Wilson an awardwinning
经历吗？我是瑞贝尔·威尔逊，一位屡获殊荣的
Hollywood Superstar okay here we go my
好莱坞巨星。好吧，我来说说我的经历。我
dad would say horrible things to my mom
爸爸会对我妈妈说一些很伤人的话，比如“又
fat lazy cow no one will ever love you
胖又懒的母牛”、“没人会爱你”。
and I had issues with food cuz I had low
我因为自卑而有饮食问题，所以
self-worth and that's why I would trash
我会糟蹋
my body I felt my life wasn't going to
自己的身体。我觉得我的人生毫无意义。
be anything but then I found
但后来我找到了一些
motivational tapes that said the brave
励志磁带，上面说勇敢的人会
put down their fears and go forward and
放下恐惧，勇往直前。
so I decided to go out into the world
于是我决定走出去，
and make a name for myself and then I
闯出一番名堂。然后我
noticed on stage that people like
注意到，在舞台上，人们喜欢
laughing at bigger people I thought I
嘲笑身材丰满的人。我想我
could use this to my advantage I gained
可以利用这一点。我增重了很多，
all this weight my body was like at 102
体重一度达到102
kilos and then I came to America now I'm
公斤。然后我来到美国，现在我靠
making millions of dollars from playing
扮演胖胖的搞笑女孩赚了数百万美元，过着令人
amazing life but you achieve it and then
艳羡的生活。但是，当你获得这一切之后，你仍然觉得
it's not enough and there was still a
不够。我仍然是个
virgin never dated properly and this
处女，从未真正谈过恋爱，而且
biological clock you could hear it
我能感觉到我的生物钟在滴答作响。
going I went to the fertility doctor and
我去看了一位生育专家，
the doctor looks me up and down and goes
医生检查了我的情况…… 然后，我意识到
you're not healthy and it like really
自己身体不好，这让我很沮丧，
sunk in I've got to fix this but as soon
我必须解决这个问题。但当
as I started telling people in my team
我开始跟团队成员说起这件事时，
they're like oh no no no why would you
他们却说：“哦，不不不，你为什么要
want to lose weight cuz then you lose
减肥？那样你会失去
your multi-million dollar career you're
你那价值数百万美元的事业，你会毁掉一切的。” 那是
your hardest moment no the darkest point
你最艰难的时刻吗？不，
in my life was when I was 13 and
我人生​​中最黑暗的时刻是在我13岁的时候。
congratulations Dio gang we've made some
恭喜Dio的粉丝们，我们取得了一些
progress 63% of you that listen to this
进展！63%的
podcast regularly don't subscribe which
定期收听我们播客的听众没有订阅，
is down from
比之前的
69% our goal is 50% so if you've ever
69%有所下降，我们的目标是50%。所以，如果你
liked any of the videos we've posted if
喜欢我们发布的任何视频，或者
you like this channel can you do me a
喜欢这个频道，能不能帮我个忙，
quick favor and hit the Subscribe button
点击订阅按钮？
it helps this channel more than you know
这对频道的帮助比你想象的要大得多。
and the bigger the channel gets as
正如
you've seen the bigger the guest get
你所看到的，频道越壮大，我们邀请的嘉宾就越有分量。
thank you and enjoy this episode
谢谢大家，祝你们收听愉快！
[Music]
[音乐]
rebel I I think to understand somebody
反叛者。我认为，要了解一个人，
you have to understand their earliest
你必须了解他/她早期的
context and as I read through your book
经历。当我读完你新
Rebel Rising which is out now I was
出版的《反叛崛起》这本书时，我有
surprised in many ways but also the
很多惊讶之处，但也……
person that I'd seen on a screen made
我在屏幕上看到的那个人，从很多
sense in a bunch of different ways so
方面来说都很有道理，所以
let me throw that question to you as the
我想把这个问题作为
first question which is if I if I was to
第一个问题问你：如果我要
Endeavor to understand you what do I
努力了解你，我
need to know about your earliest
需要了解你早期的哪些
context yeah I guess some people say on
经历？嗯，我想有些人会说，他们在
screen and they have this image of what
屏幕上看到的你，会给你留下某种印象，
you are like um and often I guess people
嗯，通常人们会
would think some overly
认为你非常
confident uh very confident in her
自信，对自己的性魅力非常自信，
sexuality and uh you know just a kind of
嗯，你知道，就是那种有点
brash ballsy person but uh from my
鲁莽大胆的人。但是，就我的成长
upbringing I mean I think I couldn't be
经历而言，我觉得我恰恰相反。
more the opposite I mean I grew up in a
我在一个
pretty regular Suburban Australian up
很普通的澳大利亚郊区
springing but was extremely shy to the
长大，但我非常害羞，
point where like you'd never think that
你绝对想不到
I would choose entertainment for a
我会选择娱乐行业作为职业，这对我来说简直是
unimaginable uh for this ex like
不可想象的。我的害羞程度几乎达到了
bordering on some kind of social
某种社交
disorder
障碍的程度。
shyness and and then coming from quite a
而且，我的出身也很
humble beginning of being in a family
卑微，我们家靠开着
out of a yellow Caravan at dog shows and
一辆黄色旅行车在犬展上卖宠物用品赚钱，
so driving around the country to these
所以我们开着车在全国各地的
dog shows and selling like pooper
犬展上卖东西。
scoopers to pick up the poop for the
铲屎铲用来清理
dogs and uh brushes and leads for the
狗屎，还有狗刷子、
dogs and and all these things and so it
狗绳等等这些东西，而且
wasn't also I was allergic to dogs so
我对狗过敏，所以
that's why my uh my childhood always
我的童年总是
felt a little bit uncomfortable which I
感觉有点不自在，
never realize why until later when I got
直到成年后做了过敏测试才知道原因。
allergic and H and so I think by by
我觉得通过
writing the book uh people can see this
写这本书，人们可以看到
whole other dimension of me and kind of
我的另一面，也许也能理解我为什么会有
personality that that I have now what
现在这样的性格。
about your parents so my mom was a
那么你的父母呢？我妈妈是
school teacher in in state schools um so
公立学校的老师，
students that came in not knowing
教过很多难民学生和不会说
English and and she mainly taught
英语的学生，她主要教
kindergarten so like all these kids so
幼儿园，教的都是这些孩子。
she's just like a light you know light
她就像一道光，
of a woman like just a brilliant teacher
一位杰出的老师，
helped so many young people and some
帮助过很多年轻人。在
parts of my childhood she was just a
我童年的某些阶段，她是一位全职家庭主妇，
stay-at-home um Mom which I shouldn't
我不应该这么
say just cuz now I'm realizing uh being
说，因为我现在意识到，当
a mom is like the hardest thing ever and
妈妈是世界上最难的事情。
then my dad was someone who his his
我爸爸的
father died uh suddenly when he was 18
父亲去世了。 呃，突然，在他18岁，
in his final year of high school uh
高中最后一年的时候，呃，
so uh I think that through his life what
所以，呃，我认为
was supposed to be his life off course
他的人生轨迹偏离了轨道，
and he kind of had emotional issues from
他因为父亲的突然离世而产生了一些情感问题，而且
from losing his dad suddenly that young
父亲的去世
um and in a tragic way so he um he had I
方式很悲惨。所以，呃，我
believe you know wanted to be a
相信他想成为一名
businessman and wanted to be successful
商人，想获得成功，
but I guess because of his own emotional
但我想是因为他自身的情感
issues and stuff didn't quite fully
问题等等，他并没有完全
achieve his his
发挥出他的
potential how do
潜力。
you know that your father didn't quite
你怎么知道你父亲没有完全
achieve his potential what were like the
发挥出他的潜力？有哪些
symptoms of that CU you seem to be quite
症状？你似乎很
sure that that that was um in something
确定这其中有什么原因，呃，
I think cuz he was so angry all the time
我想是因为他总是很生气，
and money was a source of um uh fighting
而且金钱成了家里争吵的根源。
so H and I just like so for example we'd
比如，我和H会
go to the racetrack with the horses and
去赛马场看马，
my dad sometimes would own like a oneth
我父亲有时会
or 12th of a racehorse in a Syndicate um
在一个赛马集团里拥有一匹赛马的十分之一或十二分之一的股份，呃，
and he'd look at the other High Flyers
他会看着其他那些“高飞
rich people who had had a lot of money
人物”，那些有钱有势、
knew their names and stuff and I
家喻户晓的人。 诸如此类的事情，我
definitely saw that he wanted to be that
确实看出他想成为那样的人，
but he wasn't that nobody was coming up
但他并没有做到，没有人走过来和
to him and shaking his hand or admiring
他握手，也没有人欣赏
him and then in in one of the um
他。后来，在
chapters of the book I write about I
我写的那本书的某一章里，我
found this gym bag in the back of his
发现他车后座有个健身包，里面
car and I was full of all these
装满了磁带。
cassettes and I just took them nobody
我就把它们拿走了，没人
ever said anything uh why they were
问过为什么会在
there or what and I noticed they were
那里，或者它们是什么。我注意到它们
all motivational tapes um and the one
都是励志磁带，其中
that I clearly remember was one called
我印象最深的是一盘叫《
How to Win Friends and Influence People
人性的弱点》的磁带。
and I think this was my father's way of
我想这是我父亲
trying to improve himself and trying to
试图提升自己、让自己变得
be better and a lot of the tapes were
更好的方式。很多磁带都是
about business about selling and um how
关于商业的，关于销售的，以及如何在
to be better in in business and and so I
商业上做得更好。所以我
feel like what even though we never
觉得，虽然我们从未
openly discussed it I feel like why
公开讨论过，但我还是想知道，
would he have those kind of things cuz
他为什么会有这些东西？因为
he wanted to better himself just don't
他想让自己变得更好，只是我
think he had the the ability to and then
觉得他没有能力做到。
his life just didn't go in the way that
他的人生并没有按照
he wanted to and I think uh because of
他想要的方式发展，我想，可能是因为
the death of his father he just never
他父亲的去世，他似乎一直无法
emotions properly um that was the best
正确地处理自己的情绪。 嗯，那可能是最好的
way probably nowadays you would go to
办法。现在，你会去找
someone and get diagnosed with what kind
人诊断
of issues you had or seek therapy or or
自己有什么问题，或者接受治疗之类的，来克服
trauma but I guess back in Australia in
创伤。但我想在
those days that wasn't thing um and so
当时的澳大利亚，这并不是普遍的做法。所以
he was a man who just you know wanted to
他是一个想要变
be better but then just couldn't like uh
好的人，但却做不到，他缺乏
emotional skills that trauma eventually
情感方面的技巧。创伤最终总会
finds an outlet either way if you don't
找到出口，如果你不
address it through like therapy it finds
通过治疗来解决，它就会以
other ways to manifest itself and what
其他方式表现出来。
were those ways and I think with him it
那些方式是什么呢？我想对他来说，就是
was being H angry and he would just turn
愤怒。他会
from all of a sudden talking normally to
突然从正常说话变成
he would go really red in the face like
脸涨得通红，就像
like a red balloon suddenly like his
一个红色的气球突然
face would almost expand and he go
膨胀起来一样，他的脸变得
really red and he'd just have these
通红，然后他会突然爆发，做出一些
absolutely like Angry outbursts where
可怕的事情，
he' do and say horrible things and and I
说一些可怕的话。我
think that that was probably stemming
想这可能
from when he lost his father in an
源于他父亲的离世，
unfair way um and and he just didn't
他不
know how to deal with it so probably
知道该如何面对。所以，如果
like you know if he was now and if you
他…… 现在，如果你
know I would be like oh you know you
知道的话，我会说，哦，你
should talk to someone a professional
应该找个专业人士谈谈，
and process your emotions properly and
好好处理一下你的情绪。
but but then back then I guess we didn't
但是，那时候，我想我们真的不
we didn't really know what to do or say
知道该怎么做或说什么，
that was just his personality to bring
这就是他的性格，他总是把这件事摆到
this into into light I guess the the
台面上来。我想，
example you given in the book is when
你在书中举的例子是，
you I think you were 12 or something
你大概12岁左右，
years old and you decide you were young
你觉得那时候你还小，
it was the summer it was hot and you
夏天很热，你
decided to wet the bed to cool yourself
决定尿床来
down mhm yeah we got back from a dog
降温。嗯，是的，我们刚参加完一个犬
show and it was really hot sometimes in
展回来，天气真的很热，在
Australia we have like these really hot
澳大利亚，有时候会遇到
like 36° days and so we thought well
36度的高温天气，所以我们想，不如把
we'll pour water all over the mattress
水倒在床垫上，把
to like wet it down so we'd kind of be
它弄湿，这样我们躺在上面就会
coolness um and then my father came in
凉快一些。然后我爸爸进来了，
and just he thought I think we'd
他觉得我们真的
literally wet the bed you know like gone
尿床了，你知道，就像在
to the toilet on the bed which we never
床上上厕所一样，我们以前绝对
would have done we were like looking
不会这么做。现在回想起来，
back we were like the most well- behaved
我们简直是
children you could imagine um and he
你能想象到的最乖的孩子。他就像……就像
just like he just it was like a flick
拨动开关一样，
switch would flick you know and he'd
你知道的。 他会
just go really angry and would just
突然发火，然后
start whacking us and it was just
开始打我们，嗯，
um it was I don't know it just seemed to
我不知道，感觉好像有什么事惹恼了
it just something would tick him off or
他，
something and he'd Just Lose It um and
他就突然失控了。那是其中一次，
that was one of the incidents but I was
但我当时年纪
really young I think I was about eight
很小，大概八岁吧。
okay and my sister was Six Liberty and
我妹妹莉伯蒂六岁。
when I spoke to her about writing the
我跟她聊起写这
book and she was like she doesn't
本书的事，她说她不太
totally remember that exact instance but
记得那件事的具体细节了，但她
she remembers several others that are
记得好几件
very similar MH um things but that one I
很相似的事情。不过那件事我
just remembered really clearly and then
记得特别清楚，然后
I felt like a terrible person cuz I
我就觉得自己很坏，因为我当时
thought oh well why did I wet the sheets
想，哦，我为什么要弄湿床单
and the mattress and I was trying to
和床垫？我当时只是想让自己
cool down but that was wrong and I
凉快下来，但那样做是不对的，我
should never been naughty like that um
不应该那样淘气。嗯，那件事一直让
to me that that particular time but that
我耿耿于怀。但这种事经常
was something that would happen you know
发生，
and this sort
这种
of physical aggression and emotional
肢体暴力和精神
abuse would continue to your mother as
虐待也会发生在你妈妈身上，
well it would extend to your mother as
也会延伸到你妈妈身上。是的，
well yeah more with my mom it was more
我妈妈那边更多的是
emotional abuse like um come home and
精神虐待，比如，她回家后会
say oh fat lazy cow what have you done
说…… 哦，你这头又胖又懒的母牛，你今天一整天都干了些什么？还有，比如“
all day um stuff like oh you know when
你知道什么时候该
to over love you um just like these
过度爱你”之类的，诸如此类的话会
comments that would just come constantly
不断冒出来。此外，还有经济上的
and also more financial abuse like he'd
虐待，比如他会
take control of the finances but then go
控制家里的财务，然后拿去
and gamble with the money and then we'd
赌博，结果我们就
have no money and um so so more with
没钱了。诸如此类的事情还有很多。
that um but with the kids it was more
但对于孩子，更多的是体罚，
the you know the physical hitting which
你知道，这在
area I grew up in I mean I know now like
我长大的地方并不罕见。我的意思是，我
now I just would never but back then it
现在绝对不会打我的孩子，真的不会，但在当时这很
it was quite common and we did have
常见。我们家有些
family friends that their dad would hit
朋友的爸爸会用皮带打孩子，这
even worse um so we kind of felt like
甚至更糟糕。所以我们感觉自己
like we didn't know anything that
好像不知道还有
different it was quite common I I ask
别的选择，这很常见。我问
those particular questions because it I
这些问题是因为我
often think that we learn our first
常常觉得，我们对
model of what love is and what a
爱和人际关系的第一个认知，
relationship is by what we observe with
是通过观察
our parents and for me I know for sure
父母的行为而形成的。对我来说，我确信，
that watching my parents how they
观察父母的
interacted left me with a message that I
互动方式，让我明白我
absolutely do not want to be in a
绝对不想谈恋爱，
romantic relationship and I avoided that
所以我一直都在回避恋爱关系。 是的，我这辈子可能都是这样，所以可能
why I never dated anybody ever um
我从来没谈过恋爱。
because I saw my parents my mom kind of
因为我看到我父母，我妈几乎
became a shell of a woman and had to
变成了一个空壳，她必须
have every ounce of strength in order to
竭尽全力才能
get out of that relationship eventually
最终摆脱那段关系，大概在
when I was like 16 17 and that left me
我十六七岁的时候。这让我
thinking I will never get
觉得我永远都不会
married um I I don't want to be in a
结婚。我不想和
partnership with somebody like this is
这样的人建立伴侣关系，这太
terrible uh because often when my dad
糟糕了。因为我爸经常
would have his Outburst or whatever it
发脾气，或者其他什么情况，都是
was always at home it was not in public
在家里，不在公共场合，
it was not around other people it was
不在其他人面前，就只是在家里。
I went who would want that like there
我想，谁会想要那样？这里面根本
was nothing loving about it and and I
没有爱。我
think even though I had one boyfriend
想，虽然我十六岁的时候交过一个男朋友，但
when I was 16 and and then he uh cheated
他
on me with a friend and and then I was
和朋友出轨了，然后我就觉得完了。
like that's it and and then from then
从那以后，整个
throughout the whole of my teenage and
青少年时期和
20s like did not date one person
二十多岁，我都没谈过恋爱，
because I guess I I didn't want to be
因为我想，我不想像
like my mother and and have this like
我妈那样，
awful thing happen that you know
发生那样可怕的事情。
obviously now the story is great for my
当然，现在我妈的故事很精彩，
mom she's now um engaged to a great man
她…… 现在，我和一个很棒的男人订婚了，他
and who's awesome and so kind and loving
很棒，非常善良体贴。
but uh my only representation I guess
但是，我唯一的榜样大概
was their marriage and it was awful like
就是他们的婚姻，那段婚姻糟透了。
it was just even when they separated it
他们分居后，花了
took seven years to uh where and
七年时间才最终解决，
basically left them my mom with nothing
基本上让我妈妈一无所有，
because all the money went to the
因为所有的钱都给了
lawyers um from the separation costs and
律师，也就是分居期间的费用。
I was just like oh like why would I want
我当时就想，
that I go no I would like to be
我为什么要那样？不，我想要
successful and go out into the world and
成功，想要走向世界，想要闯出一番
make a name for myself and a romantic
名堂。
relationship would only cause me pain
恋爱只会给我带来痛苦，只会
only drag me down uh not allow me to be
拖累我，让我无法做
my true
真正的
self um so I thought yeah I just thought
自己。所以我想，是的，我以前觉得
I would never never i' never wanted one
我永远都不会想要恋爱，
until you get real lonely when you
直到你功成名就，感到无比孤独，
become successful and then you're like
然后你才会想，哦，
oh maybe maybe things can change what am
也许情况会改变，
I going to do with all this stuff yeah I
我该如何处理这一切？是的，我
think some of my darkness comes this is
觉得我的一些阴暗面来自我父亲，这是
a quote from your book I think some of
你书中的一句话。
of my family a lot of dodginess when you
我父亲那边肯定有犯罪史，有很多不光彩的事情。你
say a lot of my darkness it's it's
说我的很多阴暗面，这很
interesting because I remember sitting
有意思，因为我记得我曾经坐在那里……
with Tim Grover who I reference a lot
我经常提到蒂姆·格罗弗，他
and Tim Grover was the guy who coached
执教过
Michael Jordan and um
迈克尔·乔丹和
Kobe Bryant for pretty much you know the
科比·布莱恩特，几乎涵盖了
most significant parts of their career
他们职业生涯中最重要的时期。是的，
yeah I think I've listened to that epod
我想我听过那个播客，太棒了，我是个
yeah yeah amazing biger basketball fan
篮球迷，是的，
yeah yeah yeah he's it was incredible
他讲得太好了。
and one of the things you said to me
你之前跟我说过，
earlier was that everyone has their dark
每个人都有阴暗面，这
side and then which is often from their
通常源于他们
early experiences and all those kinds of
早期的经历等等。很多时候，
things and then it's often our light
我们光明的一面也是由
side is often created by our dark side
阴暗面塑造的。是的，
in many respects yeah so I see shades of
我在
in those early years of of your um story
你的早期经历中看到了你阴暗面的影子。
but when you say that your dark side
你说你的阴暗面
probably came from your father what are
可能来自你的父亲，
you referring to so I kind of feel like
你指的是什么？我感觉，
um that I have friends in the industry
我在业内有一些朋友，他们的
childhoods and you know and and to me
童年非常美好，但
sometimes in their work they come across
有时他们的作品却显得平淡无奇。
vanilla and and then I was thinking
然后我就在想，为什么他们的作品不够
interesting or something and they're
精彩呢？他们
great and they're talented but it's not
很棒，很有才华，但就是不够
as interesting and I normally when I you
吸引人。通常情况下，当我…… 你
chat to them you find out oh they have
跟他们聊天，会发现他们有
two loving parents and they had a great
两个慈爱的父母，
childhood um and so for me I think why I
童年也很幸福。所以我觉得，我之所以
have certain parts of my personality and
有我性格中的某些特质，
like to do comedy and stuff is because I
喜欢喜剧之类的，是因为我
have this I have a lightness which
身上有一种轻松的气质，这
definitely comes from my mom and my
肯定来自我妈妈和
mom's side of the family that are all
她那边的亲戚，他们都是
like that and then on my dad's side it's
这样。而我爸爸那边，到处都是些不
just like dodginess everywhere and like
靠谱的人，比如
like I don't you know alcoholism and
酗酒、
like addictions and um and and just also
上瘾之类的，还有一种
a mentality of just I don't know how to
心态，我不知道该怎么形容，只能说
explain it best apart from saying it's a
有点儿不靠谱。
sometimes when uh I mean I don't suffer
有时候，我虽然没有
from like actual depression or whatever
抑郁症之类的，
but then sometimes if you're feeling
但有时候，你会感觉自己
like you're a you know uh sometimes I
像个……你知道，有时候会有一种
it's feels like a mafia sensation when
黑手党的感觉，你会想“
you're like oh I want to get revenge on
我要报复
those people or something you know uh
那些人”之类的。
I'm like shocked of where these feelings
我很惊讶这些感觉是从哪儿来的，
come from and they're normally from the
它们通常来自
Dark Side um but if I didn't have that I
黑暗面。 如果没有那些，我
don't think I'd be as interesting as a
想我作为
as a person or as a performer um and I
一个人或者一个表演者都不会那么有趣。嗯，我
definitely like have sometimes have an
确实喜欢有时候在
edginess to jokes and stuff which I
玩笑之类的东西里带点尖锐，我
guess I wouldn't have had if I if I
想如果我没有那种特质，我就不会有这些。
didn't have you know one side of the
你知道，我家族的一方有点
family be be a bit dodgy um and the
古怪，
other side be light so I knew I knew the
另一方则比较轻松，所以我知道其中的
difference and I knew I kind of had both
区别，我知道我两者兼具。
you embody both and that's quite
你同时体现了这两种特质，这很
interesting yeah when someone can
有意思。是的，当有人能
present us both at the same time a
同时展现我们这两种特质时，甚至
little bit sadistic as well
有点虐待倾向。
but in the in the in the cover of your
但是，在你的
book it says um that you're always
书封上写着，你总是
questioning am I good enough I can
质疑自己是否足够优秀。我能
relate for many reasons of my own to do
理解你的很多感受，
with like coming here when I was do you
比如我刚来这里的时候。
think Steven that's why you're
史蒂文，你认为这就是你
successful because you're asking
成功的原因吗？因为你一直在问
yourself that
自己这个
question I think it's intrinsically
问题。我认为这与我为什么如此积极进取有着内在的联系。是的，
to ask myself in recent years am I
近年来我一直在问自己，我是
actually driven or am I being dragged by
真的积极进取，还是被
something they both look the same yeah
什么东西拖着走？它们看起来一样。是的，
but when you're dragged it's more it's
但是当…… 你被拖着走，感觉更糟，
there's it's there's less control yeah
控制力更弱，更难
less ability to stop and slow down and
停下来，更难慢下来。
are you workoholic I read that the P
你是工作狂吗？我读到过，P
definitely so I think maybe you're also
肯定是，所以我认为你可能在
in the dragged category to some degree
某种程度上也属于被拖着走的那一类。
and my dragging came from being not
我的拖着走的感觉来自于觉得自己不够
enough in the context I was you only
好。我是
black kid poorest family in the area so
当地唯一的黑人孩子，家境最差，所以
you're there's a deep sort of sense of
你内心深处有一种
Shame and insecurity that you're trying
羞耻感和不安全感，你试图
to fill prove to others and yourself
向别人和自己证明
that you're you're not my question was
你不是。我的问题是，这种感觉是从什么时候
about when that started in you what made
开始的？是什么
made you feel like you weren enough I
让你觉得自己不够好？你能回头看看是什么让你觉得自己不够好吗？我
think I definitely get self-esteem and
觉得我肯定能从成就中获得自尊和
self-worth from
自我价值感。
achievements um and so when it was in
所以，在
school it would be getting 100% in every
学校的时候，每次
exam and that would be good if I didn't
考试都考满分，这很好；如果没考到满分，我就会
I'd feel bad about myself and then I
感觉很糟糕。然后，我
don't know just generally being
不知道，总之，
successful in things gives me makes me
成功会让我
feel good about myself but then I was
感觉良好。但后来我
thinking about one of the reasons why I
想到我以前有
had uh issues with food and because I
饮食问题的原因之一，因为我……
had low self-worth and and then I felt
低自尊，然后我觉得
like I was not good enough I was like
自己不够好，就像
trash and that's why I would trash my
垃圾一样，所以我才会糟蹋自己的
body cuz I just felt like well I don't
身体，因为我觉得自己不配
deserve anything different and then
拥有更好的。
that's a really complicated question to
这是一个非常复杂的问题，很难
work out why don't I feel good enough um
弄明白为什么我会觉得自己不够好。
and and I've thought about of a lot and
我思考了很多，有些原因
and some things I know but then some
我知道，但有些原因
things I think I I don't know why some
我不知道为什么。有些
things are as simple as like for example
原因很简单，比如在
being born a girl in the area where I
我出生的那个地区，
was from and boys were more praised like
男孩更受赞扬。
even at the dog
即使在犬
shows did something called Junior
展上，如果
handling and then if a boy ever entered
一个男孩参加一个叫做“青少年牵犬师”的项目，
he'd normally win cuz it was like oh boy
他通常都会赢，因为大家都觉得他很厉害。
doing it uh whereas girls just just
而女孩则不被
seen as being as good um the boys school
认为那么优秀。
I went to an all girls high school but
我上的是一所女子高中，但
the boys school next door was seen as
隔壁的男校被认为更有
more prestigious and better um and um
名望，更好。
theater at their school and you know it
他们的学校里有一个价值数百万美元的剧院，你知道，就是那种感觉。
um and so I think some of it is just as
所以我觉得有些原因很
simple as like being born a girl in in
简单，比如我出生在那个
the area and I was like God that's so
地区，我当时想的是“上帝”。 这真是
dumb though why didn't I um like
太蠢了，为什么我没能
transcend that
超越这种想法呢？
and then some of it must have been from
一部分原因可能是我
not feeling love although obviously I
感受不到爱，虽然我
know my parents love me very very much
知道我的父母非常非常爱我，
but um because of I came from a very
但是因为我来自一个非常
conservative family we didn't really
保守的家庭，我们很少
talk about emotions and feelings and so
谈论情感，所以我的情感
it wasn't expressed in the way that I
表达方式
probably needed it to so I I didn't feel
可能并不适合我。
good enough unless I was getting first
除非我在某个科目中名列前茅，或者得到表扬，我才会觉得自己足够好。只有
and so then I felt good um or winning a
赢得
prize or a trophy and and that's when
奖项或奖杯，我才能
you would get the praise from the people
感受到来自身边人的赞扬。所以我一直都这样，嗯，嗯，但问题是，
but then it's like I like there was
我明明没有
nothing wrong with me I go why did I not
任何问题，为什么我还是
feel good enough but I guess I've
觉得自己不够好呢？我想，我
always felt that
一直都有这种感觉。仔细想想，这其实挺
um and it's kind of sad when you think
悲哀的，
about it cuz you're like why would
因为你会想，为什么会
somebody it's not like I did anything
有人这样觉得我呢？我又没做错什么，也没该
bad or you know should have felt ashamed
感到羞愧，但
about something I just always felt like
我就是一直有这种感觉。
that I guess it proves that kids they
我想这证明孩子们
don't they're not born with perfect
并非生来就拥有完美的
self-esteem they do need that to be
自尊，他们需要后天的
fostered and poured into and nourished
培养和滋养，
or else there can be an ABS so what I'm
否则可能会出现自卑情结。所以我的
saying is there doesn't have to be
意思是，不一定非得
something that happened that proved you
发生什么事证明你
weren't good enough but there could just
不够好，也可能只是有些事
be maybe something that didn't happen
没发生，却
that proved you were and I think there's
证明了你足够优秀。我觉得有很多
all these little micro things that can
细小的事情都可能
happen um you know you're not chosen for
发生，比如你没被选中，或者你
something or you're not uh you're always
总是被冷落，或者你
you're not ever the star or just all
永远不是明星，或者所有
these little things or no one ever
这些小事，或者没人
thought you'd make it or be anything MH
认为你会成功，或者你有什么成就。
um and just like little things that
就像…… 一些小事，比如
little comments people would say or
别人说的那些小评论之类的，
something and then um yeah and then that
然后，嗯，是的，然后
all just adds up and you you're 13 14
所有这些加起来，你十三四岁，
you're in school you're shy this point
还在上学，那时候你很害羞，
I'm guessing you you have that struggle
我猜你肯定也有那种觉得
with feeling like you're good enough I
自己不够好的挣扎，我
think that's maybe a symptom of the
觉得这可能是
shyness yeah and also like I was just
害羞的表现。是的，而且我长相也
very average looking I had like a
很普通，还有一颗龅牙，
snaggle tooth what's a snagle tooth it's
龅牙是什么？
like a basically a deformity like a
基本上就是牙齿畸形，
deformed tooth like on one side which
一侧牙齿变形，
I've had fix now but kind of like a Fang
我现在已经矫正了，但有点像獠牙，
I guess but only on one side so it
不过只有一侧，所以
wasn't like some cool vampire thing I um
不是那种很酷的吸血鬼牙齿。嗯，
and then I had that and I was so
然后我就有了这颗牙，我特别
painfully shy where I'd go red in the
害羞，
face if a teacher asked me to answer a
如果老师
question in class even though I knew the
在课堂上问我问题，即使我知道
answer it was just it was so
答案，我也会脸红，这太
embarrassing and I didn't have any
尴尬了，我没有
friends um and I guess because I thought
朋友，嗯，我想是因为我当时想，
why would people want to be friends with
为什么会有人想和
me I'm not good-looking or popular or
我做朋友，我又不好看。 或者说，
cool in any way and and so I just yeah
在任何方面都不受欢迎或很酷，所以，是的，那真的是我人生中最
of the darkest times like when I like 13
黑暗的时期之一，大概在我
14 and and like you know people are kind
13、14岁的时候，你知道，那时候人们开始有点儿
of becoming the M themselves at that
变成“M”了。
point and then I read this article in
然后我在图书馆读到一篇文章，
the library that said that what your
说你
personality is at 15 will be your
15岁时的性格会决定你
personality for Life uh because I used
一生的性格。因为我以前经常一个人
to eat my lunches in the library just by
在图书馆吃午饭，所以总是看书。
time and then I read this and I went
然后我读到这篇文章，心想：
like I'm so close to 15 if I don't
我快15岁了，如果我不
change this is going to be me forever
改变，我这辈子就都是这样了。我
and can I imagine my life like not
能想象我的人生吗？不
expressing anything to anybody just like
跟任何人交流，只是
being just shy and introverted and isol
害羞、内向、孤僻。我
at ated and I just knew I didn't want
知道我不想那样，那
that that that wouldn't have been the
不会是
happy life for me and not that there's
我幸福的生活。当然，害羞没什么
anything wrong with being shy like the
错，
sh sometimes can be like a superpower
有时候害羞就像一种超能力。
You observe people and you um you know
你可以观察别人，
you learn a lot by by
通过观察学习很多东西。
observing but then I just was like no I
但我当时就想，不，我
want to have friends and I want to have
想要朋友，我想要…… 我觉得
fun and be popular and and so I was like
有趣又受欢迎，所以就想，
oh well I better get a move on and
好吧，我得赶紧行动起来。
luckily I found those motivational tapes
幸运的是，我找到了那些励志磁带，
and then and then they helped me um
它们帮了我很大的忙。
because I thought I want to be somebody
因为我一直想成为一个能
that expresses myself like literally
表达自己的人，就像你
you'd look at me uh and I sometimes see
看着我的时候，我有时会在
it in my niece now I think she has a
我的侄女身上看到类似的情况，我觉得她也有
similar thing like it's almost like you
类似的问题，就好像你根本察觉不到发生了
wouldn't be able to register anything
什么，
that's going on you wouldn't know if I'd
你不知道我今天过得好不好，我就是面
just be like no no expression or
无表情。
anything um and then I I was like okay
然后我就想，好吧，
I'm going to force myself to like come
我要强迫自己
out of my little cocoon or my shell or
走出我的小茧，或者说我的壳，或者随便
um whatever the metaphor is and just
什么比喻，总之要
break out and with the help of those
突破它。
tapes and like it having a strategy and
有了那些磁带的帮助，我制定了一个策略，并且知道该
how to do it what was the strategy uh
怎么做。策略是什么呢？嗯，有很多
well there were all sorts of things but
方法，但
I remember from that how to win friends
我记得其中有一条是关于如何赢得朋友
and influence people there was something
和影响他人，那就是
about talking to five new people every
每天和五个新朋友交谈。
day and so that was one of the first
所以这是
things I did and like talking to girls
我做的第一件事，比如在公交车上和女孩聊天，
on the bus or just you know walking up
或者…… 你知道，走进
through the school Gates and talking
校门，和
just talking to the person next to me
旁边的人聊聊天，打个招呼，然后
and saying high and what you realize is
你就会意识到，
that there's other people as lonely and
原来还有其他人跟你一样孤独寂寞，跟陌生人
day to speak to somebody new and you
说句话可能就是他们一天中最开心的事。与其
library all day waiting for friends to
整天坐在图书馆里等着朋友来找
find me which they never would why don't
我（他们永远不会来），不如
I actively go out and join like SP other
主动出去，加入
sport teams or other clubs at the school
学校的运动队或其他社团，积极地去交
and like actively try to make friends
朋友。
like it's not just going to happen if
如果
you're just doing nothing um so there
你什么都不做，朋友是不会自然而然出现的。所以，我学到了一些
were these little tips and
小技巧和
strategies um but one of which was to
策略，其中之一就是要
get
引起
attention which was to be essentially to
注意，也就是要做一些
be naughty to get attention it's kind of
出格的事来博取关注。就像说唱
like that uh you know Eminem the rapper
歌手埃米纳姆那样，
if he hadn't put out all these songs
如果他没有创作那些
that were like really controversial and
极具争议、歌词内容惊世骇俗的歌曲，
would he have been a successful rapper
他还能成为一名成功的说唱歌手吗？
probably not and so it was kind of like
恐怕不能。所以，
I then to do some dodgy things at school
我当时也想在学校里做一些出格的事来
to get known to get like a reputation
出名，建立自己的名声，但这跟
which was against my natural personality
我原本的性格完全不符。
cuz I was such a good little girl um but
因为我小时候是个很乖的小女孩，但为了引起
get attention and then that led to
注意，我不得不做一些出格的事，然后就变得
popularity then once you have the
受欢迎了。一旦你有了
popularity you don't need to do that
人气，就不需要再做那些
stuff but yeah is there some kind of a
事了。但是，
link there between you the career you
你
would then pursue as an actress as a
后来从事的演员、
performer
表演者、
um a comedian all of those things and
喜剧演员等等职业，和你
this sort of early desire to have
早期渴望获得
attention and validation from you know
关注和认可之间，是否存在某种联系呢？
your PE I think it started from just
我觉得这最初只是源于
like a more normal thing about wanting
一种更正常的想法，比如想要交
to have friends M and wanting to be
朋友，想要被
invited to some parties and um so it it
邀请参加派对等等。所以，它就是从
started it started from that and and
这些开始的。
like and then you wanted to be respected
然后，你渴望得到尊重，
but then to be respected people first
但要获得尊重，人们首先
have to know who you are and so
要知道你是谁。所以
sometimes you have to do that
有时候，你必须做出一些
attention-seeking behavior to get that
引人注目的行为才能获得尊重。至于
um but but the how I got into like
我如何进入演艺圈，其实是
acting was really well my mom dragged me
我妈妈把我拉
into it because um I mean the studies on
进去的，因为学习
that creative arts can really help your
艺术真的能提升
self-esteem and self-confidence it's
自尊和自信，简直
like insane like it's really good for
太棒了，对那些
young people who are struggling and my
正在挣扎的年轻人来说真的很有帮助。我
mom could see me like struggling and
妈妈也看到了这一点。 就像我以前很挣扎，
having no friends and so mom takes me to
没有朋友，所以妈妈带我去
these drama classes at this community
社区中心上戏剧课，她
center and literally has to drag me out
几乎是把我从车里拖出来的，
of the car I'm holding on to the car
我当时
door with my fingernails like going no
用指甲抠着车门，不停地说“
no no I don't want to go it was so
不不不，我不想去”。那段时间对我来说太
traumatic but she was doing it not
痛苦了。但她这么做并不是
because she wanted me to become an actor
想让我成为演员，因为我们
entertainers in the family like you know
家没有从事演艺行业的人，你知道，
uh nobody I know was in the business or
我认识的人里也没有谁是这行的。她这么做
whatever at that point it was more to
更多的是为了
self-esteem through the creative arts
通过艺术创作来增强我的自信心和自尊心。
and weirdly it really did because when
奇怪的是，这真的奏效了。因为像
you're shy like I was to play different
我这样害羞的人，扮演不同的
characters it's like an escape because
角色就像是一种逃避，因为那
it's not really me it's a different
不是真正的我，而是一个不同的
character and and then you can perform
角色。你可以扮演那个
as that person and then eventually some
角色，然后最终，一些
of that confidence starts coming to you
自信会慢慢回归到真正的你身上。
but obviously at the time nobody thought
当然，当时没有人认为
I would become a professional actress or
我会成为一名职业演员，或者
they would have laughed about that
他们会嘲笑我的
scenario it's it's interesting because
想法。这很有意思，因为
you can see these different drives
你可以看到
forming within you you've got this drive
你内心深处正在形成不同的动力，
for um I don't know you might say for
比如…… 我不知道，你可能会说是为了获得
validation externally but then because
外界的认可，但因为
you come from a family that didn't have
你来自一个并不富裕的家庭，所以
money there's also where you were
你才会因为
rewarded for academic success or being
学业上的成功或其他方面的成就而受到奖励。
this drive to be successful which shows
这种渴望成功的动力在
up in early in your story when you start
你故事的早期就有所体现，比如你开始
selling things and buying things and
买卖东西，
then you do exceptionally well in school
然后在学校里表现得非常出色，
um you go off to board boarding school
你去了寄宿学校。
it's what a 16 years old I think in part
我想，对于一个16岁的孩子来说，
it sounds like to escape from the
这在某种程度上是为了逃离
childhood the household dynamics of your
童年，逃离父母的家庭环境。
father and your mother yeah um you do
是的，你在
exceptionally well there as well
那里也表现得非常出色，非常出色。
exceptionally well and then you end
然后你最终去了
up in Africa South Africa I know which
非洲，南非，我知道这很
is random uh so you know a lot of people
突然。你知道，很多人都会选择
do the Gap here thing and I mean it's
间隔年旅行，我的意思是，这很
random but basically as a witness in a
突然，但基本上，在
major crime Squad investigation when I
我高中最后一年的时候，我作为证人参与了一起重大犯罪调查，
was in my final year of school i'
我
witnessed something and had to testify
目睹了一些事情，不得不出庭作证。
and then uh through that some people
然后，通过这件事，一些人对
were very impressed with my ability to
我
go and do that in a case and so I was
在案件中的表现印象深刻，所以我就……
like and and they told me about this
他们向我介绍了这个
program that was uh it's a rotary
项目，这个项目是…… 这是一个扶轮社
program and it was called a youth
项目，叫做青年
Ambassador um program and basically they
大使项目。基本上，他们
wanted young people who were very good
需要一些非常擅长
at public speaking and by this point I'd
公开演讲的年轻人。那时
done I'd forced myself to do debating
我已经强迫自己参加辩论
and public speaking and to get over my
和演讲，克服了我的
shyness and so I was quite a good
羞怯，所以我的
speaker and and I got recommended into
演讲能力相当不错。有人推荐我参加了
this program and got selected and you
这个项目，我被选中了。你
don't get to choose what country you go
不能选择去哪个国家，
to they they just select for you so and
他们会为你随机分配。
they sent one boy and one girl from our
他们从我们区派出一男一女去
district over um to different countries
不同的国家，
and I got given South Africa and I was
我被分配到了南非。
like Co cuz I thought it was going to be
我当时想，哇哦，因为我一
like The Lion King at first which was
开始以为会像《狮子王》那样，那是
one of my favorite movies and then I go
我最喜欢的电影之一。然后我到了
apartheid and it was so different to
种族隔离制度结束后的几年，那里和
Australia like Australia's very safe
澳大利亚截然不同。澳大利亚非常安全，而
murder rate in the world at that time
当时的约翰内斯堡强奸和谋杀率是世界上最高的，
and there were guns everywhere and
到处都是枪支、
bobbed wir fences and you know attack
铁丝网围栏和攻击
dogs and it was like it was so eye
犬。这真是让我大
openening but then to
开眼界。但同时，我也必须
also uh be constantly aware of the
时刻警惕
violence and like I had to carry a
暴力，比如我必须随身携带一
little like a wooden baton like what you
根木棍。 就像卡通片
see like an old you know policeman in a
里老警察用的那种警棍，
cartoon would would carry because I
因为
literally if somebody attack me I'd have
如果有人攻击我，我就得用它
to hit them on the head with it and it
打他们的头。当时我就觉得
was like I was like this is crazy like
这太疯狂了，
that year um and but that's how I got
那一年发生了很多事。嗯，我就是因此得了
the malaria uh which forced me to have
疟疾，疟疾让我有了
this Vision that I was to become an
成为
actress and I think if I'd never ever
演员的预感。我想，如果我没
gone to Africa I never would have had
去过非洲，我就不会有这个
that life-changing vision and I probably
改变人生的预感，我可能
just would have gone back to law school
只会回到法学院，
and and being being a lawyer in in
然后成为
Australia me and you both share that in
澳大利亚的一名律师。我和你都有这个
common we both were in Africa and got
共同点：我们都去过非洲，都被
bitten by mosquito you have a vision I
蚊子咬了。你有一个预感，我也有一个预感，
had a vision what was your vision so I
你的预感是什么？当时我
my dad was holding so we're in our house
爸爸抱着我，我们在家里，
and they didn't know that I had malaria
他们不知道我得了疟疾。
this is what my dad and my mom tell me I
这是我爸妈告诉我的，我当时还
was very young they were holding me here
很小，他们抱着我，
and I was I'd woken up in the night
我半夜醒来，说床边有个
because I said there was a man by my bed
男人。
so they' picked me up thinking oh my God
他们把我抱起来，心想：我的天哪，
there's this man in his bedroom and that
床边有个男人。 在他的卧室里，
when my dad was holding me like this so
我爸爸这样抱着我，让
I can see over his shoulder the man
我能从他肩膀后面看到那个人，那个人就在
would be behind him and I was freaking
他身后，我当时吓坏了，觉得他
out that there's a man behind him um
身后有个男人，
which I was later would call the shadow
后来我把这个人叫做“影子
man and wrote a little novel about when
人”，我大概14岁的时候还写了一本关于
I was about 14 and this this shadow man
这个影子人的小说。
um because I was losing my mind they
因为我当时精神状态很差，他们把
took me to a hospital and at hospital
我送到医院，在医院里
they found out that I had malaria but in
他们发现我得了疟疾，但
hindsight they tell the story that
事后他们说，是
that's that man saved my life oh you
那个人救了我的命，你
know what I mean so I grew up very I
知道我的意思。所以我从小就一直觉得
grew up with this idea that I had a
我有一个
guardian angel
守护天使，一个
the shadow man but it was just malaran
影子人，但那只是疟疾引起的
hallucinations yeah well like tell about
幻觉。嗯，说说
your hallucinations I had a n nasty
你的幻觉吧。我得了一种很严重的
strain of malaria and um it was put in
疟疾，然后被送进了
hospital and you know malaria is so diff
医院。你知道疟疾很不一样，
I don't know whether you remember
我不知道你还记得不记得，
because how old you but it's it felt
因为你当时多大了，但感觉就像我感觉自己
like just felt like I was not in my body
不在自己的身体里一样。
and and then they take me into hospital
然后他们把我送到医院，
and give me these drugs and then I then
给我用了药，然后
I just started hallucinating and I
我就开始出现幻觉了。 我出现了
hallucinated that I was an actress that
幻觉，觉得自己是个演员，演技
I was so good that I win an Academy
好到能拿奥斯卡
Award and I must have I mean I'd seen
奖。我肯定看过
the Oscars on TV I'd obviously never
奥斯卡颁奖典礼，当然我没
been and um and then I just walked down
去过现场。然后我就走下台，感觉太
the and it was so real like I could see
真实了，我能看到
all the people with the dresses and I
所有穿着礼服的人，
get up on stage and then I give an
然后我走上台，用说唱代替了
acceptance rap rather than an acceptance
获奖
speech because I thought oh yeah that's
感言，因为我觉得这样很酷。
hardcore and at one point I had want I
我曾经一度
had wanted to be a rapper because of
想当说唱歌手，因为
their coolness and Swagger um didn't
他们很酷，很有范儿。嗯，我和
group with my sister yeah didn't work
妹妹组了个小说唱组合，但没成功。幻觉太生动、
and it was so vivid and real like I
太真实了，我至今都记得。然后
it and then I came out of hospital I was
我出院了，我在
in hospital for two weeks I came out and
医院住了两周，出院后我就想，
I was like I think I've got to become an
我得去当
actress now i' had this vision and
演员了，因为我有了那个幻觉。
people go a no like the malaria has
人们说，不，疟疾
affected your brain they they're just
影响了我的大脑，他们觉得
thought I was crazy and I go no I've
我疯了，觉得我疯了。我说，不，我亲眼
seen it and they're like no no no like
看到了。他们说，不，不。 不，就像
you've you've got into the best law
你考上了
school in Australia like maybe go to law
澳大利亚最好的法学院，也许可以去读
school and have a great career and I'm
法学院，然后拥有辉煌的职业生涯，但我当时想，
like no I've seen it and I and I think I
不，我已经看过那些了，我觉得我
need to be an actress now and then I
现在需要成为一名演员。然后我
left South Africa a month earlier I was
提前一个月离开了南非，本来我
supposed to be there a full 12 months I
应该在那里待满12个月的，但我提前
left one month earlier uh to audition
一个月去
for a drama school in Australia which I
澳大利亚参加一所戏剧学校的面试，结果被
got rejected because obviously I was
拒绝了，因为我表现得很
terrible um and and nobody looked at me
糟糕。没有人注意到我，也没有人想到我可以当
and go actress nobody so
演员。所以，
um yeah and
嗯，是的。
and it still took I think from that
从我产生那个想法到
Vision five years until I really got it
真正明白
you could make money from acting H but I
可以通过演戏赚钱，我觉得花了五年时间。但那感觉就像是
it was like the vision came to me and I
灵感突然降临到我身上，我
watched a lot of Oprah and Oprah was
看了很多奥普拉的节目，奥普拉说过，
like well the universe will tell you
宇宙会告诉你，一开始会像
like first it'll come in little Whispers
耳语一样悄悄地出现，
And then it'll be like bricks falling on
然后就像砖头砸在
you and I was like but see I've I've had
你身上一样。我当时想，但是你看，我已经有了那个
the vision I have to I have to do acting
灵感，我必须，我必须去演戏。
now um in hindsight yeah was that a
嗯，现在回想起来，那到底是
malaria hallucination or was it divine
疟疾引起的幻觉，还是神的
intervention I don't know I think is was
旨意？我不知道，我想那可能是某种…… 我一直
that some subconscious desire that I was
潜意识里有个愿望，但我从来
never brave enough to say to
没勇气跟
anybody um because I was in the high
任何人说。因为我
school musicals and plays um you know in
高中时参加过音乐剧和话剧，你知道，在
the musical I was like never cast as the
音乐剧里我从来没演过
lead or whatever but I really enjoyed it
主角什么的，但我真的很喜欢，真的非常喜欢。
like I I really did enjoy it and so but
但
I just never thought someone like me
我从来没想过像我这样的人
could have a career in that area so I
能在这个领域发展事业。所以我就在想，这
was like was that just a subconscious
只是潜意识里的
desire that just decided to come out
愿望，在
when I was deathly ill or was it some
我病入膏肓的时候突然冒出来了吗？还是某种……
kind of I don't know some higher power
我不知道，某种更高的力量在
or something showing me that this was
告诉我，这才是
more my purpose um cuz I remember a lot
我的使命？因为我记得
thinking that time like what is my
那段时间我一直在想，我的使命是什么？
purpose like what am I supposed to be
我
doing in the world and I'd write in my
在这个世界上应该做什么？我会把这些写在我的
little diary you know like but again I
小日记里。而且，我
watched a lot of Oprah so I was like you
看了很多奥普拉的节目，所以我就在想，
know what's my purpose how can I give
我的使命是什么？我该如何
back to people those tapes as well yeah
回馈社会？那些录像带也是。
probably so you go back to Australia you
所以你回到澳大利亚，去
pursue law I guess for the money you
学法律，我想是为了赚钱吧，你
just thought that was a good well
觉得那是个好选择，
because my father had dropped out okay I
因为我父亲辍学了。好吧，我
definitely wanted to have a college
当然想拿到大学
degree and he always said that was his
学位，他总是说他
biggest regret that he never got his
最大的遗憾就是没能完成他的
business degree and because i' got I was
事业。 因为我考上了法学院，而且
so hard to get into this law school you
这所法学院很难进，你
almost had to be near perfect in all
几乎必须在所有考试中都接近完美，
your exams so I just thought I may as
所以我就想，我干脆也去考吧。
well just do it as well will you ever
你有没有想过要
more than the other oh my mom just
更努力地给父母中的一个留下深刻印象？哦，我妈妈只是
wanted her dream for me was to be normal
希望我能像个普通人一样，
I guess like you know to have friends to
你知道，有朋友，有
kind of have a you know relationship and
人际关系，
be kind of normal so it's not like she
过着普通人的生活。所以她
definitely didn't want me to be some
肯定不希望我成为
kind of a known public person sometimes
公众人物。有时候，作为家里的
the oldest sibling you're the oldest of
老大，你是
four right is a bit of a reflection of
四个孩子中的老大，这在某种程度上反映了父母的期望，更确切地说，
more so of a reflection I think of what
我认为这在某种程度上反映了
the parents wanted for themselves I tend
父母对自己的期望。
to think that's a bit of a so I'm
所以我想知道，
wondering if your like desire for
你对
success and valid if it was something
成功的渴望是否合理，是否源于
that you felt from your father like you
你父亲的期望。你
know him he couldn't be that himself so
知道，他自己做不到这一点，所以
maybe he reflected that more praise on
也许他会在
you when you were objectively successful
你取得客观成功的时候更多地赞扬你。
in the things that you did um why would
嗯，
you want to be a lawyer is yeah I just
你为什么想当律师？嗯，
because if you were smart you'd go into
因为如果你聪明的话，你会去
Laural medicine um and and so you know
学医的。嗯，所以你知道的。
and they would have loved to have gone
他们肯定很乐意到处炫耀，
around and said you know oh my
说“我
daughter's a lawyer at this firm and
女儿是这家律所的律师”，那会是一份多么
that would have been a great you know
棒的
great career that they would have
职业啊！他们会觉得
thought that my parents had to work
我父母为了
really hard to send me to the school
供我上这所我
that I did like at one point apart from
喜欢的学校，一定非常努力工作。有段时间，除了
selling all the dog products my dad was
卖狗用品，我爸爸还在
also working at the gas station
加油站
overnight and you know just to afford my
上夜班，就为了能负担得起我的
school uniforms and stuff like that so
校服之类的东西。所以
so for them a successful outcome would
对他们来说，一个成功的结果就是：
have been okay she got into the top law
她考上了顶尖的
school and now she's going to be a
法学院，现在她要成为一名
lawyer and therefore all that money
律师了，因此所有花在
spent on education was worth it and you
教育上的钱都是值得的。你
go back you do end up qualifying as a
回去后，最终确实能成为一名
lawyer yeah um you become a lawyer
律师，是的，嗯，你确实成为了一名律师。虽然我花了
it did take me 10 years though it's
十年时间，但
normally a 5year double degree and I did
通常来说，双学位只需要五年，而且我还读了
Arts as well um why did it take so long
文科。嗯，为什么花了这么长时间？
cuz you're acting so basically yeah so I
因为我在演戏。基本上，是的，我一开始会参演
would I'd be in theater shows at first
话剧，然后
and then it would be TV shows and my law
是电视剧。我的
school had an 80% attendance rule so
法学院有80%的出勤率要求，所以
basically if I started in a semester and
基本上，如果我一个学期开始上课，
then for some reason my filming schedule
然后因为某些原因，我的拍摄安排
or whatever I'd have to repeat the
或其他什么原因，我就…… 我不得不重复一遍这个
subject because if I didn't attend in
话题，因为如果我不亲自
person 80% of the time so it was
到场，80%的时间都会
exhausting um often I was would fly have
很累。我经常要
to fly into State I'd be filming in
飞到
another state I have to get up at 4:00
另一个州去拍戏，我得凌晨四点起床
a.m. in the morning and fly to Sydney to
飞到悉尼去
law school and then fly all the way back
法学院，然后当晚再飞回来。
that night from the from the first time
从你第一次尝试
acting gig or tried to be an actress to
表演，或者说第一次尝试当演员，到
the moment when you feel like you had
你觉得自己成功了，这要
made it how many years is that so I
多少年？
started quite late I guess I started
我开始得比较晚，
like 18 turning 19 which is quite late I
大概18岁快19岁的时候才开始，我觉得挺晚的。
think I think a lot of people start kids
很多人12、13岁就开始了，
yeah 12 13 I guess um and then that was
嗯。然后我上了
like proper acting classes like proper
正规的表演课，那种真正
like with people wanting to do it as a
想把表演作为
career and then I had I wrote my first
职业的课。21岁的时候我写了我的第一个
play at 21 I just wrote it in two nights
剧本，只用了两个晚上就写完了，
and then it won this playwriting
然后它赢得了一个剧本创作
competition and got put on um and I was
比赛，还被搬上了舞台。我当时就想，我的天哪！
like holy crap um and then a television
然后一家电视台
station gave me $90,000 to put it on
给了我9万美元，让我把它
professionally which was like kind of
专业化地推广出去。 这简直太疯狂了，
great luck for the first thing I'd ever
我写的第一部作品就这么成功，真是太幸运了。
written um and I realized from that
从那时起，我意识到
point nobody saw me as an actor I wasn't
没人把我当演员看待，我不是
like Nicole Kidman or that you know in
妮可·基德曼那种类型的演员。
that vein so I realized pretty quick I
所以我很快意识到，
had to write myself my own material if I
如果想成功，就必须自己创作剧本。
was going to make it but I didn't start
但
wage um until I was a regular on a TV
我直到23岁成为电视剧的常驻演员后，才开始赚到全职的职业收入。在
being an act do you realize that your
成为演员的道路上，你会在哪个阶段意识到自己的
weight is influencing how people see you
体重会影响别人对你的看法
and the way that they're casting you so
以及他们选择你出演的角色呢？大概
when I was like uh about 21 into like
21到
22 uh I had something called PCOS
22岁的时候，我得了
polycystic aarian syndrome and one of
多囊卵巢综合征（PCOS），
the key signifiers of that was like
其中一个主要症状就是
rapid weight gain so all of a sudden I
体重迅速增加。
mean when I first started acting I was
我刚开始演戏的时候，身材很
just a regular side was a bit athletic
普通，有点运动型，
looking but you know pretty regular um
但就是很普通。
and and then all of a sudden I gained 30
然后突然之间，我胖了30
kilos and was like and I had some other
公斤，而且还有一些其他的
symptoms as well I had like some dark
症状，比如
hair on my arms and there there's a
手臂上长了一些黑毛。 那里有
couple of key signifiers to it and then
几个关键的征兆，然后
I went to the doctors and they said oh
我去看了医生，他们说，哦，是的，
yeah you've got PCOS and in that first
你得了多囊卵巢综合征（PCOS）。在
play that I'd written when I was 21 I'd
我21岁写的第一部剧本里，我
cast a girl who was bigger than you know
选了一个比我体型大很多的女孩来演，你知道，她体型
quite a large girl and then I noticed on
相当大。然后我注意到，在
stage like did get way more laughs than
舞台上，她比
me and I kind of wrote all the roles
我更能博得观众的笑声。我写的每个角色都差不多，
quite evenly and I was like why is that
我就想，为什么那个
girl getting getting more laughs and I
女孩更能博得笑声？说
honestly thought I mean one she's
实话，我当时想，一方面，她很
hilarious but it's cuz she's bigger and
搞笑，但另一方面，是因为她体型大，
people like laughing at bigger people
人们喜欢嘲笑体型大的人。
and then there I did this subject at
后来我在
University called comedy and power and
大学里选修了一门叫做“喜剧与权力”的课，
basically you know there is a science to
基本上，你知道，这里面是有科学依据的。
if you normally if you want to sleep
通常情况下，如果你想
with somebody you're not nor wanting to
和某人上床，你不会想
laugh at them so you know if you want to
嘲笑他们。你知道，如果你想
sleep with someone you're into them
和某人上床，你会对他们感兴趣，被
attracted to them but normally the
他们吸引。但通常情况下，
people that you want to laugh at are
你想嘲笑的人是那些
people that have some kind of immediate
有某种明显的
physical irregularity like you know
生理缺陷的人，比如，你知道，体型
bigger women do do well in comedy um you
较大的女性在喜剧界往往很受欢迎。你
might be really tall really short you
可能很高，也可能很矮，或者你的胸部
might have a really big nose something
很大。 鼻子，
something about you that's quite
你身上有某种非常
distinctive um that people can instantly
独特的东西，嗯，人们能立刻
go aha you know and they in more in
恍然大悟，你知道吗？在
comedy the science of it is more people
喜剧领域，科学原理是，更多的人
want to be your friend rather than they
想和你做朋友，而
don't want to be your lover they they
不是想成为你的爱人，他们
want to be your friend and they think
想和你做朋友，他们觉得和你一起出去玩、一起开怀
and have a laugh with and so it was
大笑会很愉快。所以，
really interesting when I gained all
当我
this weight I was like ah I think I'm
体重增加的时候，这真的很有意思。我想，啊，我想我应该
going to lean into comedy because um
转向喜剧，因为嗯，
even though I tried to be a serious
虽然我一开始尝试过成为一名严肃的
actress at first I was like hang on this
演员，但我后来想，等等，这
which could be seen as a huge negative a
可能被视为一个巨大的缺点，
lot of people would be going oh no you
很多人会说，哦不，你
know I put on all this weight instead I
知道，我胖了这么多。但我却
went the opposite way and was like you
反其道而行之，我想，
bigger as just what you know a good tool
你知道吗，我可以利用这一点，我喜欢喜剧，我想我应该去演喜剧，把体型变大当作一个优势。 这是
in my comedy toolbox and then that was
我喜剧工具箱里的一件工具，后来
kind of reinforced I guess because then
我觉得这一点得到了强化，因为
you people laugh harder and then they
观众笑得更厉害，他们就会
pay you more and and it is true it is is
付你更多钱。这是真的，
true people like laughed laughed more
真的，观众笑得更厉害了，
and I lent into comedy and then I got a
我也开始专注于喜剧。后来我拿到了
scholarship from Nicole Kidman
妮可·基德曼的奖学金
uh to go to New York and I went to a
去纽约，当时我在
second City Comedy School in New York at
纽约的第二所城市喜剧学校学习。
the time um and yeah and then I just
然后我
realized I had a quite a good knack for
意识到自己在这方面很有天赋，
it and that was taking off more than the
而且喜剧比
dramatic acting how did you feel about
戏剧表演更受欢迎。你当时对自己感觉如何？嗯，我
well I guess uh I was quite shocked in
想，
my Diaries when I looked back at them
当我翻看日记
for research for the book even when I
为这本书做研究时，我相当震惊。即使我
was 16 and I wasn't big at all I was
16岁，身材也不胖，而且
very athletic played lots of different
运动能力很强，参加过很多不同的
sports and and my first goal was like to
运动，我的第一个目标竟然是
lose two kilos I guess cuz my mom had
减掉两公斤，我想是因为我妈妈曾经说过
made a comment at some point not not for
一句话，
any bad reasons she just you know
她并没有恶意，只是
thought she had weight issues herself
觉得她自己也有体重问题，觉得
and just thought you know if I lost
如果我减掉
those two kilos I might feel better in
那两公斤，我可能会感觉更好之类的。
myself or something like that and so I
所以，我就……
just when I gained all that weight there
当我体重暴增的时候，我内心其实很
there's kind of a dichotomy cuz at one
矛盾。一方面，
point I'm like this could help me
我觉得这或许能帮我
professionally in comedy and you know
在喜剧界发展，你知道，
big girls do do better in comedy I can
胖女孩在喜剧界确实更容易成功。我感觉自己
see a pigeon hole for myself in that
在这个
area and you can be successful and I'd
领域找到了自己的定位，而且也能获得成功。23岁的
just gotten on a television show when I
时候，我上了一个电视节目，
was 23 playing kind of the I guess the
扮演一个……嗯，
whale character is what they sometimes
他们有时会这么
refer to me as and they refer to you as
称呼我，或者叫我“
the whale character yeah well like I was
鲸鱼角色”。是的，我扮演的是
the obese girlfriend of one of the guys
一个男演员的肥胖女友，
who he was embarrassed to go out with me
他觉得和我约会很尴尬。
so the whole joke was like he was trying
整个笑点在于他想把我
to hide me because he didn't want people
藏起来，因为他不想让别人
to know I was in a relationship cuz I
知道我谈恋爱了，因为我
was obese and that was the whole it was
太胖了。这就是整个节目的梗。这个
very popular show in Australia it's
节目在澳大利亚很受欢迎，
called fat pizza and and so on the one
叫《胖披萨》（Fat Pizza）。所以一方面，确实如此；
hand there's that but then on the other
但另一方面，
hand I felt
我知道
like I knew I was eating very badly I
自己当时的饮食习惯很糟糕，基本上就是
carbs pretty much I remember coming to
碳水化合物。我记得刚到
New York and going to Comedy school and
纽约，去喜剧学校的时候，每天都要
you know just eating a pint of ice cream
吃一大杯冰块。
for dinner or a whole big bag of chips
晚餐吃奶油，或者一大包薯片之
or something and and then and I so on
类的，然后，
the one hand I could be confident and
一方面，我自信地认为
know that this could be good for me
这对我的
careerwise but on the other hand I
事业有好处，但另一方面，我
knew I'm not treating myself right this
知道我这样对待自己不好，这
is not good you know I'm not being
不好，你知道，我不健康。
healthy um and so I had both going on in
所以，我
my mind at the same time how do you play
脑子里同时想着这两件事。你
a role in a movie that fat Pizza movie
在电影里扮演一个角色，就像《胖披萨》那样，
where you're basically
你基本上扮演的是别人觉得
somebody else is embarrassed
尴尬的某个人，
about and how does that not impact your
这怎么可能不在某种程度上影响你的
self-esteem at some level cuz I'm
自尊心呢？因为我在
thinking if I was playing in a movie
想，如果我在电影里扮演一个
someone an individual that someone was
别人
trying to hide the thing is like cuz
试图隐藏的人，那感觉就像，因为
when it's acting it's not quite you and
表演并不是真正的你，
only on a rare occasion would people
只有极少数情况下人们才会
confuse
混淆，因为很
like cuz obviously the guys on the show
明显，剧组的人在
camera and everything um it was that was
镜头外都很棒，很尊重我，等等。那
just the character I was playing and I
只是我扮演的角色，我
was lucky to be on a comedy show and uh
很幸运能参加喜剧节目，并以此
to be earning money that way but then I
赚钱。但后来我
remember going to a post office and just
记得我去邮局寄东西…… 收到
like mailing a letter and the guy was
一封信，那人
obviously a fan of the show and started
显然是节目的粉丝，开始
saying oh Tula that was my character oh
说：“哦，图拉，那是我演的角色，哦，
he's so fun you know and like he in real
他太有趣了！”你知道吗？就像他在现实
life was saying stuff like the guy on
生活中也像
the show but this is now real life yeah
节目里那样说话，但这可是现实生活啊，是啊是啊，
yeah yeah and it was very hurtful in in
这在
real life whereas for acting it's you
现实生活中真的很伤人。而演戏嘛，你
know kind of can separate it a little
知道，可以稍微区分一下。
bit what did you say to him that day
那天在邮局，你跟他说什么了？
that post post office I didn't say
我什么也没说，就直接
anything I just kind of walked out and
走了出去，
thought Oh that guy's an idiot he
心想：哦，那家伙真是个白痴，他根本
doesn't understand the distinction
分不清
between a comedy show and you know a
喜剧节目和
real person and and so that was just a
真人。所以，这有点
bit hurtful um but it but I guess it
伤人，嗯，但我想肯定是这样。
must but then on the other hand it it's
另一方面，我很难
feel sorry for myself because then
自怜自艾，因为
obviously not in Australia but then when
在澳大利亚肯定不会这样，但当
I came to America and played like Fat
我来到美国，扮演了“胖
Amy which
艾米”——这
is probably my most famous character I
可能是我最著名的角色——
mean now I'm making millions of dollars
之后，我靠
from playing the the fat funny girl and
扮演这个胖胖的搞笑女孩赚了数百万美元，而且我
really leaning into that and
非常投入这个角色。还有什么比数
millions of dollars or the you know what
百万美元更重要的呢？你知道
I mean and that's well now I care about
我的意思吗？嗯，现在…… 我很关心
my health and wellbeing but but back
自己的健康和福祉，但当时
then I guess I thought oh well I'm
我想，好吧，我正在
becoming successful and this is helping
走向成功，而这（指某种生活方式或事业）正在帮助
me become successful I think this is
我走向成功。我认为这正是
really at the heart of what your book
你这本书的核心所在：
that you know we can become quote
我们可以
successful in the eyes of the world but
在世人眼中获得所谓的“成功”，但这
that doesn't necessarily mean we're
并不一定意味着我们
successful holistically in all the
在所有
things that we need to to be successful
需要成功的事情上都取得了全面成功。我对此
and I I I relate to that so much because
深有体会，
because of the things we've described
因为我们之前描述的那种被
about being driven and dragged and all
驱使、被拖累等等，
that stuff I think I became successful
我想我可能只在成为全面发展的人所需的
in one of maybe the 10 things that I
十件事中的一件上取得了成功。是的，
person yeah and anomalies like you that
像你
achieve such great success often there's
这样取得巨大成功的特例往往需要做出一些权衡。是的，我
a trade-off yeah so I felt like I needed
觉得我需要
like Olympic Athlete dedication to make
像奥运选手那样的奉献精神才能
it in the entertainment business I mean
在娱乐圈取得成功。我的意思是，
the odds of making it are so small one
成功的几率非常小，
to make it in my home country and then
在我的祖国取得成功的几率是一分之一，然后
to come to Hollywood and to make it um
来到好莱坞，再取得
really of having the career that I've
我这样的事业成就的几率更是百万分之一。
had um so you know like an Olympic
所以，你知道，就像奥运会运动员一样。
gymnast if you meet people and they're
如果你遇到一些体操运动员，他们
gymnastics but then you talk to them um
体操技术非常出色，但当你和他们聊起
about their personal life or their their
他们的个人生活或
skills and uh and then
技能时，
basically you can tell they're like
你会发现他们好像受到了某种
stunted I guess is the is the right word
阻碍，我想用“阻碍”这个词比较贴切。他们曾经
um so they've had this drive and this
拥有过那种动力和
focus and they've achieved and they if
专注，也取得了成就，比如
you're an athlete you know like get to
参加
the Olympics or or to me like being in
奥运会，或者像我一样参演
an Oscar nominated movie um I haven't
一部奥斯卡提名电影。我当然没
won obviously the vision hasn't come
得奖，梦想也没实现。
true um but but was I stunted I was like
但我感觉自己受到了阻碍。
if you really knew me you'd know that
如果你真的了解我，你就会知道，
until my early 30s I hadn't had that in
直到30岁出头，我才第一次约会。我几乎没有过
Intimate experiences
亲密关系，
and uh and relationships and so all that
所以这
area of my life like wasn't great but I
方面的生活并不顺利。但我可能是
ever come out of my high school or you
我高中毕业后最成功的人，你
know so like there were great things I
知道，我有很多很棒的经历，比如
could go courtside at the LA Lakers
可以去洛杉矶湖人队的比赛现场看球，等等。
stuff but then there was
但是，
like yeah on a personal side I wasn't
在个人生活方面，我却遇到了一些问题。 一方面，我并不是个
the the best person and then I then I
完美的人，后来我
knew that I knew oh God okay so I've
意识到，哦，天哪，好吧，我
excelled in one area but now there's
在一个领域很出色，但在
and the other area was apart from love
其他方面却很欠缺。除了爱情
life and kind of social life was also um
和社交生活之外，还有
Health you have you move to America um
健康方面。你搬到美国，然后
you get um you work very hard for the
努力工作
next couple of years you get this you
几年，终于得到了一个机会——出演《
know this opportunity in bridesmaid
伴娘》，但
which then takes some time for it to
之后还需要一段时间才能看到结果。
come out I read in your book that you
我在你的书中读到，你出演《伴娘》的
got paid $3,500 for your role in
片酬是3500美元，这真是太令人震惊了。是的，那是
yeah that my first job in America and I
我在美国的第一份工作，
mean I was very lucky to to get it I
我很幸运能得到这个角色，能出演
mean what an awesome cracker over a
一部
movie to get that but to be paid that
电影真是太棒了，但片酬却这么
little and basically that $3,500 I then
低，基本上那3500美元我还要
had to pay to the union to join the
交
union so I basically I made no money I
工会会员费，所以基本上我没赚到钱，反而
lost money because I had to pay to go to
赔了钱，因为我还要花钱去参加
the premere like to buy my dress and
首映礼，买礼服
everything so I lost money doing
等等，所以出演《伴娘》我赔了钱。
bridesmaids but and then you have to
然后你还得等，
wait it normally takes a whole year when
通常要等很久。
you film a movie for the movie to be
拍完一部电影后，等它
released so that was a really skint year
上映的那一年，我的生活非常拮据。在
where I was living on $60 a week in La
洛杉矶，我每周只靠60美元生活，这笔
and that's not a lot of money so like I
钱根本不够用。所以我根本
wasn't partying or living living this
没时间去参加派对，也没享受什么奢华的
life it was
生活，
basically just having that Focus trying
基本上就是专注于
to write for myself like going to
写剧本，参加
auditions and um and I had to wait a
试镜等等。我等了
whole year till bridesmaids came out and
一整年，《伴娘》才上映。结果
then suddenly it comes out there this
它突然爆红，
big hit and I book six movies off the
我因此接到了六部电影的邀约，其中一部就是《
Perfect uh which was kind of my real
完美音调》。这部电影简直是我的“
golden ticket um that movie and became
金票”，它成为了史上票房
the highest grossing musical comedy
最高的音乐喜剧系列电影。是的，参与这些
very very very successful and very very
非常非常非常成功、非常非常棒的
awesome fun movies to be a part of so
电影拍摄真的很有趣。
they're they're like such a gift those
这些电影就像一份礼物，它们
movies your life changes at that point
改变了我的人生。
because you you're sort of globally
因为你
internationally famous now and surely
现在在全球范围内都成名了，你肯定会觉得一切都结束了，可以
that means job done we can we can chill
放松一下，
we can go look at other things and I say
可以去做其他事情了。我
this because there so many people me
这么说是因为很多人，包括我自己，
told ourselves in the past that once we
过去都可能这么想过。 一旦我们像《
hit the Pitch Perfect the global Smash
完美音调》那样在全球范围内取得巨大
Hit success then we'll chill then you'll
成功，我们就可以放松一下，你们也会很
be happy and then it'll be fine and then
高兴，一切都会好起来的。当然，
uh but then of course then you come up
之后你们又会提出
with some different goals that I'm like
一些新的目标，我觉得这
is even harder you guys may have heard
更难。你们可能已经听说了
our most recent news the launch of
我们最近的消息，
flight Studio which is our brand new
Flight Studio 正式上线，这是我们全新的
podcast and media technology company as
播客和媒体技术公司。随着
we scale this new company we also need
公司规模的扩大，我们也需要
to scale our team and my first Port of
扩大团队。Flight Studio 的招聘首选平台是
been link LinkedIn jobs who are a
LinkedIn Jobs，它是我们
sponsor of this podcast we're hiring for
播客的赞助商。我们目前正在招聘
around 30 to 60 roles right now and
30 到 60 个职位。LinkedIn
Linkedin has been me and my teams goto
一直是我和我的团队的首选
their platform makes the hiring process
平台，它让招聘流程
intuitive smooth and super efficient
直观、流畅且高效。LinkedIn
LinkedIn has helped me and my team
帮助我和我的团队
Source professionals we can't get
找到了其他任何地方都找不到的专业人才，
anywhere else even those who aren't
甚至包括那些
actually searching for jobs right now
目前没有求职，
but might be open to the perfect role
但可能对加入我们公司担任理想职位感兴趣的人。
with us in a given month over 70% of
超过 70% 的
LinkedIn users don't visit other leading
LinkedIn 用户不会访问其他主流
job websites they visit LinkedIn so if
求职网站，他们只会访问 LinkedIn。所以，如果
you're not not looking on LinkedIn
你不在 LinkedIn 上找工作，那
you're looking in the wrong place so
你就找错地方了。
today I'm giving the dire of coo
今天，我要向大家介绍一下首席运营官的
Community a free LinkedIn job post head
社区。 免费发布LinkedIn职位，请
to linkedin.com
访问linkedin.com，
doac now and let me know how you get on
立即申请，并告诉我结果。
terms and conditions apply a real P
条款和条件适用。你人生
pivotal moment and turning point in your
中真正的关键时刻和转折点
life is clearly when you went to that
显然是你
doctor that day after deciding that you
决定要孩子后去看医生的那天。
wanted to have a child mhm yeah why did
嗯，是的，
you decide you wanted to have a child
你为什么决定要孩子？有什么
was there an influence something you'd
影响吗？你
seen or something I yes I never thought
看到了什么？是的，我从没想过，
cuz I was so career driven I thought uh
因为我一心扑在事业上。
you know I'd never thought I would want
你知道，我从没想过要组建
to have a family um and also being in my
家庭。而且，我的
business it was so so egocentric the
工作环境非常以自我为中心，
business um and so I just didn't think
所以我根本没想过要孩子。
that was in the cards for me and I also
我
thought oh well I'm probably never going
还想，哦，我可能永远也
to find a partner or whatever and then
找不到伴侣什么的。然后，就像
inside me when in my late 30s just
我体内的生物钟，在我快40岁的时候，突然
started like ticking really loudly and I
开始滴答作响，声音非常大。我感觉就像
kind of say it's like imp Peter Pan and
彼得·潘和
that crocodile that has the clock inside
那只肚子里有钟的鳄鱼，
it it was just like like you could hear
你能听到
it going tick tick tick I was like do it
它在滴答滴答地响。我心想，
now like it'll otherwise it'll be too
现在就生吧，不然就……
late and I would see babies on the
太晚了，我看到街上有很多婴儿
street with their moms and be like a and
和他们的妈妈，
I just like keep staring at all the
我就一直盯着那些
babies and and just like like I just
婴儿看，心里涌起一股强烈的想要当
a mother and even though I didn't have a
妈妈的渴望。虽然当时我没有
partner at that point and I just was
伴侣，但我还是
like uh I think I should uh try
想，我应该试试。
and and but I was getting I was like 39
我当时39
years old and I didn't even know that I
岁了，甚至不知道自己还有
had eggs or what could be done and um
卵子，也不知道该怎么做。
and then I went to the fertility doctor
后来我去看了不孕不育医生。那时候我的生活非常精彩，
this really large like you know I am
你知道，我属于
medically obese but I'm living this kind
医学意义上的肥胖，但我过着一种
of amazing life I traveled the world I
很棒的生活。我环游世界，
learned how to have fun and uh not be so
学会了如何享受生活，不再那么
much of a workaholic and I was like you
工作狂。就像
know like that lizo song like it's bad
Lizo那首歌里唱的“It's Bad
o' like that was like my life like
Bitch O'”一样，那简直就是我的生活写照。
I'm walking around just loving it I've
我到处走走，享受着生活，
been successful now and then the doctor
现在我很成功。然后医生上下打量了我一番，说：“是
goes yeah but you're not healthy and he
啊，但是你身体不太好。” 他
said you have a much better chance of
说：“你现在的几率更大。” 问我是否
having a baby if you were healthy and
健康，要不要生孩子。
the way he said it with like kind of
他说话的
quite a lot of disdain in his voice I
语气里带着相当轻蔑，我当时就懵了，
was like huh cuz that's that was a
因为他是个
stranger most people you know in
陌生人。你知道，好莱坞的大多数人
Hollywood they're not going to come up
不会走过来跟
to you and go oh you're engaging in bad
你说“哦，你的
you know eating habits obviously like um
饮食习惯很差”，他们只会说“哦，
they're just like oh congratulations on
恭喜
your new movie and yay it's great um you
你的新电影上映，太棒了！你
play Fat Amy and that's awesome and how
演胖艾米，真了不起！电影这么
successful it's been uh I don't think so
成功！”。我觉得
he wasn't in my
他不是我的目标受众，
demographic he looked a bit like the
他长得有点像《
doctor from Doc from um Back to the
回到
Future okay yeah older guy with white
未来》里的博士，嗯，一个上了年纪、头发花白的家伙。
wiry hair so yeah I don't think he was
所以，我觉得他不是我的
in the pit perfect fan base and he just
铁杆粉丝。他竟然当面这么
he just said it straight to my face and
说，
then I go oh I'm not healthy cuz and I
然后我就说“哦，我的确不健康”，其实我内心
knew deep down I just suppressed those
深处知道，我只是压抑着这种
feelings but I knew deep down I wasn't
感觉。我知道自己
healthy but I didn't have any serious
不健康，但我并没有什么严重的
diseases I was doing incredible things
疾病，我在世界各地做着很多了不起的事情，
all around the world so I just didn't
所以我根本没想过要生孩子。
and then he said that and it like it
然后他说了那番话，我感觉就像被狠狠地
really sunk in it was like this
敲了一下脑袋，这
criticism that was I couldn't ignore and
批评我无法忽视，
I is like oh God okay yeah he is right
我心想，天哪，好吧，他说得对，我的身体确实
and I'm not healthy um because on the
不健康。
one hand I'm like a beacon of body
一方面，我一直倡导身体
positivity and that CU I really do think
积极，我真的认为
beauty is at any size and um and and had
美不分身材，而且，到那时我已经
and had grown you know so much
建立了很强的
self-confidence um by that point but
自信心。但
then on the other hand I knew I was
另一方面，我知道自己有
engaging in unhealthy eating behaviors
不健康的饮食习惯，
and that was something I wanted to
我想
improve in myself and then I I thought
改正这一点。然后我想，
well the next year 2020 I'll make the
2020年，我要把
whole year about getting healthy like I
整整一年都用来让自己健康起来。就像我
said I'm not going to work weirdly I
说的，我不会工作。奇怪的是，我根本
couldn't have predicted that a pandemic
无法预料到会
was going to happen uh I'd already
发生疫情。我本来就
planned not to work that year and to
计划那一年不工作，用
take a whole year to do Health stuff you
一整年时间来改善健康。
doctor visit and you describe kind of
看完医生后，你回到车里，描述了你当时
your what's going on in your brain but
脑子里的想法，但正如你
you you've as you said you know at that
所说，你知道，在那一刻，你深深地意识到
point you knew you weren't healthy deep
自己的身体状况并不健康。
down deep down yeah um every one kind of
内心深处，嗯，其实每个人都
knows you know if you if you are
知道，如果你属于
medically obese you kind of know that
医学意义上的肥胖，你大概也知道。
yeah but to get from there to taking any
但是要从这一点出发采取任何
action it's really hard to to change
行动，真的很难改变这种
behavior in such a way yes especially
行为。尤其是
because I yes had I tried to go on diets
我，我以前也尝试过节食，
before had I gone on diets had I gone to
去过那种
like a little health farm and you know
小型健康农场，你知道，
lost 5 seven pounds in a week and and
一周减了5到7磅，但
then you never sustain it and then it
你根本无法保持，体重又反弹了。所以，
never tried I just never thought because
我不是没试过，只是从来没想过要改变，因为
always the weight would come back on and
体重总是会反弹。这大概就是我的
from my body was like at 102 kilos and
身体的稳态吧，我的体重一直保持在102公斤左右，就是这样。我就想，
like oh well I could never permanently
唉，我永远不可能永久
change that I just thought no I can get
改变这一点。我当时就想，不行，我可以拿到
two degrees from University and become
两个大学学位，成为
an international movie star but I just
国际电影明星，但我就是无法改变我的体重。我当时就想，
can't like with the weight I was like I
我做不到，
can't like just you know I don't know
你知道，我不知道，
I'm just not right in that area I never
我在这方面就是不行，我永远
I'll never be healthy in that
不可能健康。
way and that one comment from that
然后，那个
stranger yeah it was something in the
陌生人的一句话……嗯，
way he said it I was like sugar I'm not
他说话的方式让我觉得有点不对劲，我当时就想，宝贝，
like I'm not healthy
我又不是不健康，肯定
like and that must be what a lot of
很多
people thought they just never said it
人都这么想，只是他们从来没当面说过。
to my face um and then it was kind of
嗯，后来，这其实是一种
the motivation almost not really for
动力，与其说是为了我自己的
myself and my health but for a future
健康，不如说是为了未来的
child that I thought well now I've got
孩子。我想，现在我必须
to fix this um and work really hard um
解决这个问题，必须非常努力，
to do it because if I I I tried so many
因为如果我……我以前尝试过很多
time I don't know 20 times or whatever
次，大概20次吧，
in the past to but it always only lasted
但每次都只能维持很
a short term and then I was like well
短的时间。然后我就想，
okay but this is different cuz now the
好吧，但这次不一样，因为现在的
motivation is to have a child so that's
动力是想要个孩子，这完全是
like a different motivating factor you
另一种动力。你
want to have a child this doctor says
想生孩子，医生说
you'll have a a chance if you're healthy
如果你健康，就有机会。
you leave there that day you must also
那天离开医院的时候，你肯定也知道，有人
people are paying you millions and
付给你几百万
millions and millions of dollars I think
美元，我想
around that time that year You' made
那一年你拍
like $20 million in movies or whatever
电影赚了大概2000万美元，
um they're paying you because you fit
他们付钱给你是因为你符合
Persona that they want yeah so as soon
他们想要的形象。所以，当
as I started telling people in my team
我开始跟别人说起这件事的时候…… 我的团队成员都说：“
about this they're like oh no no no why
哦不不不，
would you want to lose weight like that
你为什么要那样减肥？
no I wouldn't if I was you I wouldn't do
不，我不会那样做。如果我是你，我就不会
that cuz then you lose your
那样做，因为那样你会失去你
you've so so successfully created and
辛辛苦苦建立起来的价值数百万美元的事业，
look at all the work you've done to get
想想你为了得到
that and now you're just going to throw
它付出了多少努力，现在你却要把
it
它
away so I was then literally like okay
毁掉。” 我当时真的在想，好吧，我
what do I do with my life am I get
的人生该怎么办？是努力保持
healthy but I lose my career or do I
健康，但失去事业，还是就此止步，
just stay the way I am and maybe never
也许永远无法生育？他们当时就是这么
of how it was positioned to me and so
跟我说的。
even though literally everyone around me
虽然我周围的人
pretty much said as you are I just felt
几乎都说“你就这样吧”，但我还是觉得
like nah I got to I think I know deep
不行。我内心深处知道
down that I'm engaging in unhealthy
自己有一些不健康的生活
behaviors and I'm going to I'm going to
习惯，所以我决定努力改善
work on my health and try to have a
健康，并尝试要个
child thinking at that point I know it
孩子。我知道这听起来很
sounds simplistic but thinking that my
简单，但我当时想的是，我的
career could be over
事业可能会就此结束。
then but I was like no it's too that's
但我转念一想，不，这
too
太
important going on that Journey losing
重要了。
the weight and all those kinds of things
减肥等等这些事情永远不会结束。
is never a straight line yeah know it's
一条直线，是的，
it was the I mean the pandemic helped a
我知道，疫情确实帮了我
lot cuz literally everything stopped um
很多，因为几乎所有事情都停止了，
and and I could just focus focus on
我可以专注于
being healthy was that became a big
保持健康，这对
blessing um to me and when I really
我来说是莫大的恩赐。当我真正
focused and did the emotional work
专注于处理情绪问题时，就像
because there's things like that I write
我
about in the book that I just never
在书中写到的那样，有些事情我以前从未
thought about until I started
想过，直到我开始
emotionally processing things did one of
处理这些情绪问题。
your contract say I think it was Pitch
你的合同里有一条规定吗？我记得是《
Perfect say that you couldn't lose 10B
完美音调》那部电影，合同里写到你不能减重10
of weight contractually yeah so that's
磅。是的，这
like quite common you can't drastically
很常见，你不能大幅
change your appearance so that's pretty
改变你的外貌，这几乎是
much in all acting contracts um it's not
所有演员合同里的条款。这
just about weight it's about your hair
不仅仅是关于体重，还包括你的发型，你知道，你的外貌，
can't go you know too much either side
你不能改变太多。
um that's basically because sometimes in
这主要是因为有时候拍
films you have to do re- shoots or
电影需要补拍，或者
sometimes you know they might want to do
他们可能想拍
a sequel or something and so you kind of
续集什么的，所以你必须
have to stay the same so literally like
保持现状。所以，我
cut my hair right now uh to a different
现在如果想剪头发，换个
color or style or whatever it's just
颜色、发型什么的，都得问别人。
to kind of look the same so this journey
这行就是这样，因为一年后你可能要补拍一部电影，所以你得保持大致相同的形象。所以，跟
weight tell me about this process what
我说说你减肥的历程吧，是什么
helped you so I was like as you can
帮到了你？就像你
probably tell like I'm quite goal
可能看得出来的那样，我是一个目标
orientated and uh and so I was like okay
导向型的人。所以我就想，好吧，
2020 is be my year of health I'm themed
2020年是我的健康之年，我把它定为主题，
it I'm going to put it on Instagram so
我要把它发到Instagram上。
I'm like held responsible yeah H you
我对此负责。你
know the other times it would be a bit
知道，以前我会更注重
more private like okay I'm going to go
隐私，比如我会去
to this health farm or whatever and I'm
某个健康农场之类的，然后我会想，
like okay it's going to be my year of
好吧，这将是我的健康之年，
health and I'm just going to focus on
我要专注于
being healthy and um the the thing Anne
健康。安妮·
haway introduced me to this doctor who
海薇给我介绍了一位医生，他
was um great cuz I guess she saw me on a
很棒，因为她看过我们
film we did together called the hustle
一起拍的电影《飞天大盗》（The Hustle），
and she kind of saw me struggling and
她看出我当时很挣扎。
his specialty was kind of dwelling into
他的专长是研究
emotional emotions and how they can
情绪以及情绪如何
affect your physical health and I never
影响身体健康，我以前从来
even thought about that like I just
没想过这一点，我当时只是
thought you know going on a diet is
想…… 节食
about eating less and exercising more
就是少吃多运动，
and um I just never thought but to me
嗯，我以前从没想过，但对我来说，
because I was an emotional eater really
因为我是个情绪化进食者，所以关键在于如何
the kicker was to process emotions and
处理情绪，
to learn how to process emotions and
学习如何处理情绪。
obviously from my family environment I
显然，从我的家庭环境来看，我完全
had definitely not learned um any skills
没有学到
in that area and was kind of holding on
这方面的技能，我总是把所有事情都紧紧抓住不放，
to everything like a so like a bag of
就像抓着一大袋
groceries of this little trauma and this
杂货，装着各种各样的小创伤，妈妈也一直记着。
and so I had to start processing that um
所以我不得不开始处理这些情绪，
with the doctor like we did a phone call
比如和医生
every two weeks and and at first it's
每两周通一次电话。一开始感觉很
awful you're like oh my God what do I
糟糕，你会想，天哪，我该
talk you know and talk about my personal
说什么？该怎么谈论我的
things and it felt awful to do it at
私事？一开始感觉很不好受，
first um and then I did it and
嗯，但我还是坚持了下来，
then gradually it kind of I started
然后渐渐地，我开始
processing things and then I could
处理这些事情，然后我就可以
release them the emotions and and then
释放情绪了，
and then the weight loss kind of came
然后体重就下降了。
but because I wasn't working I I did do
因为我没有工作，所以我做了
crazy workouts like I was working out
疯狂的锻炼，
like 2 hours 2 and 1 half hours a day um
每天锻炼2到2个半小时，为了
to help you know to help accelerated I
加速减肥，我还
was cooking my own meals I was you know
自己做饭。 你知道，我当时
concentrating on eating high protein
专注于吃高蛋白
meals and like I was just doing all the
食物，感觉自己做的一切都是
right things because I didn't have any
正确的，因为我没有
stress of work and um and I was just
工作压力，嗯，我就想，
like okay this is going to be it but the
好吧，这下总算成功了。但
real thing was the emotional what what
真正的问题是情感上的，
are those bags that you let go of
那些需要放下的
emotionally I think a lot of it like I
情感包袱是什么？我觉得很多时候，
write this book if I hadn't have done
如果我没有
that uh emotional work with the doctor
和医生一起做那些情感方面的治疗，我可能写不出这本书。
because um there was just stuff that I
因为，我
suppressed you know a lot of stuff about
压抑了很多东西，你知道，很多关于
my father and my complicated
我父亲的事情，我和
relationship with him and and the
他之间复杂的关系，还有
sadness of him dying um uh he suddenly
他去世的悲伤。他突然
had a heart attack and and died right
心脏病发作去世了，就在《
you know close after Pitch Perfect one
完美音调》上映后不久。我
came out um and I think just all these
想，
little things in my
我童年时期的这些小事，
um that you know I just I guess I
你知道，我以前
never thought that that was associated
从没想过它们和
with my weight but it obviously was and
我的体重有关，但显然是有关系的。
because I hadn't processed things it was
因为我没有处理好这些事情，就像
was like I was holding on to barriers it
我一直紧紧抓住一些障碍，体重就像一道
was like the weight was a barrier one
障碍，
for like intimacy for example you know I
比如亲密关系。你知道，我以前从来
never wanted a relationship or wanted to
不想要恋爱关系，也不想要…… 为了
be attractive or whatever and the weight
更有吸引力什么的，体重
was kind of a barrier because that kept
成了某种障碍，因为它把
all the people is do you believe that
所有人都挡在了门外。你相信吗？
I've heard that from psychologists a few
我
times even on this podcast before I've
以前在这个播客里也听心理学家说过好几次了。我
heard one particular guy called Johan
听过一个叫约翰·
har who wrote a book called Lost
哈尔的人说过，他写了一本书叫《失去的
connections tell me that in a study
联系》，书中提到一项研究，
where they looked at um women who who
他们观察了一些
were clinically obese and then they put
临床肥胖的女性，然后让
them through a weight loss program they
她们参加减肥计划。他们
found that some of the women would then
发现，有些女性减肥后
re regain weight and the Catalyst for
体重又反弹了，而导致体重反弹的催化剂是
that was them being hit on they
她们被搭讪。他们
discovered in those women that there was
发现这些女性
early sort of abuse or there was issues
早年遭受过某种虐待或其他问题，
so they made this link that sometimes we
所以他们得出结论，有时我们会
use weight as a defense from sort of
用体重来抵御
sexual advances or and I definitely was
性骚扰。我肯定也这样，
because I wanted to be in the fat funny
因为我想扮演一个胖乎乎的搞笑
friend role which I played quite well in
朋友的角色，我在
real life and on screen because I didn't
现实生活和荧幕上都扮演得很好。因为
you know I didn't want somebody to be
我不想让别人
coming home with me and then seeing how
跟我回家后看到
I really lived or felt you know why I
我真实的生活状态和感受，你知道为什么吗？
don't know I guess I just was
我想我只是觉得
embarrassed or do you remember men or
尴尬。你还记得在你20多岁的时候，有没有男人或
women hitting on you at any point in
女人搭讪过你吗？
your 20s and then actively rejecting
然后我主动拒绝了
them off so I literally was like for
他们，所以我当时就想，
some people like um but didn't anybody
有些人会问，嗯，难道没有人主动
come up to you whatever I was like no
搭讪过你吗？我就说，没有，
like I honestly don't remember one
我真的不记得
person um apart from the little
有谁，除了
boyfriend I had when I was 16 which was
我16岁时的那个小男友，那是我经历过的
the most innocent thing ever where we
最纯洁的感情，我们
just held hands and maybe kissed once
只是牵牵手，可能亲过一次。
anyways uh when I got famous from Pitch
总之，当我凭借《完美音调》走红后，
Perfect there was like a waiter at chat
在Chat
Marmont that like gave me his number and
Marmont酒店有个服务员给了我他的电话号码，
like you know basically said you
你知道，基本上就是说，
know take me home with you tonight kind
今晚带我回家之类的。
of thing and I was shocked and I was
我当时很震惊，我
there with my buddy Matt Lucas and I was
和我的朋友Matt Lucas在一起，我
like what do I do with this like it was
就想，我该怎么办？这算是我
kind of like the first attention so only
第一次受到关注。直到
when I
我
when I became very successful so that
非常成功之后，我才开始注意到别人的关注。
invisible attractiveness wise until that
在那之前，我几乎觉得自己魅力全无。
point did you text the waiter no I
你给那个服务员发短信了吗？
didn't but Matt goes you should have
没有，但是Matt说你应该发，
what are you doing go go for it and I go
你在干嘛？快去争取！我说，
Matt no like I well I was so shy in that
Matt，不，我在这方面很害羞，
area I was like I'm not just going to
我想，我不能就这么随便…… 我
bring a waiter home from the chatow
从Chatow
Marmont um we get a lot of people from
Marmont回来，嗯，我们这里也有很多
prison as well when I became famous they
监狱出狱的人。我成名后，他们会
like DM you and like go oh be my wife
私信我，说“哦，做我老婆吧”之类的，
and all this stuff like oh my God like
我的天哪，
but no like I just unless I was just so
但其实
blocked off to that I didn't notice
我根本没注意到这些，除非我完全屏蔽了这些。
anything you know I when a woman in
你知道，我
particular gets over 30 what I've heard
听说，
and especially considering some of my
尤其是考虑到我的一些
friends who are women over 30 is people
30岁以上的女性朋友，她们
around them sometimes start getting a
身边的人有时会开始
bit pushy like their friends start you
有点咄咄逼人，比如她们的
people my father would always say oh on
朋友会说“来吧，来吧，去追他吧，我会给他机会的”。是啊，你有没有感受到来自外界的这种压力？我父亲总是会问：“
The Limited times we talk oh are you
哦，我们偶尔会聊聊，你有
seeing anybody i' always get so angry at
没有对象？”我总是对这个问题很生气，
that question i' like why is he asking
心想他为什么要问
me that as if I'd want to get married
我这个问题，好像我想和
like him and my mom were and how
他和我妈妈结婚似的，
terrible that was and I'd always just
这太糟糕了。我总是
get angry at it and just be like no and
会生气，然后说“没有”，然后就
about that issue is it because it came
对这个问题彻底关闭了。是因为这个问题
from him who was yeah in particular and
出自他之口吗？是的，尤其是他。 当时我就想，
I was like oh God what like out of all
天哪，那么多人，怎么没
the people to say something most people
人说点什么呢？大多数人什么
didn't didn't say anything but I know
都没说。但我知道那种
there is that pressure like uh for
压力，就像
single women over 30 you just get like a
30岁以上的单身女性会感受到的那种压力，
little bit and but I felt it more in my
有点儿，但我在
30s um and I I went on a dating app at
30岁后期感觉更强烈。我曾经用过一个约会软件，
one point to like try to meet people did
想认识一些人，结果怎么样呢？因为
that go cuz I was like well I actually
我后来发现，我
met some good people in real life yeah
在现实生活中确实遇到了一些不错的人。是的，就像在
it was like dating at um Rya that has
Rya上约会一样，上面有
some celebrities on it they would let me
一些名人，他们会让我加入。
on it I tried when I was I tried when I
我18岁的时候就试过了，那时候
in my life but I tried and the problem
我的生活没什么进展，但我还是试了。问题
is you would have been great I think now
是，我觉得你现在应该很不错，
I think they give me a shot now but back
他们现在会给我机会，但
then I submitted my application when I
我当时19岁左右提交的申请，
was like 19 so they're still looking at
所以他们还在看
the same application and I'm still in
同一份申请，我还在
the waiting list so but now I'm in a
等待名单上。但现在我有
relationship and I don't need that so
伴侣了，我不需要约会软件了，
yeah you don't need it now so it's their
所以是他们的
loss um but I was yeah no went on and I
损失。嗯，我当时……
you know dated a few great guys and
你知道，我约会过几个很棒的男生，也
actually had had fun and it was good but
确实玩得很开心，感觉很好。但
I had to because I was so behind the
我不得不这么做，因为我在
eightball on dating and love and
约会、恋爱和
relationships like I had to almost like
人际关系方面完全落后了。就像
year of Love experiment before I did
我之前为了“健康年”做了一个“恋爱年”实验一样，在那之前，我得先尝试一下，让
of put myself out there which was hard
自己走出去，这很困难
and challenging like it's a going on
也很有挑战性。
dates and you got to get all dressed up
约会的时候，你得精心打扮，
and you know and then go and have it
然后去
lunch or dinner with someone that you
和某个你
might not know whether there's any
可能不知道有没有
chemistry and and you were a virgin at
感觉的人吃午饭或晚饭。而你35岁的时候还是个处女，没错，就是这样。所以，约会的时候，
anxiety in your brain because you know
你的脑子里肯定会有焦虑，因为你知道，
if this date goes well there might be an
如果这次约会进展顺利，对方可能会
expectation that I go to the bedroom
期待我和他上床。
with this individual yeah well that was
嗯，那都是
all later I mean weirdly the the guy I
后来的事了。说来也怪，我
lost my virginity to at 35 I was I was
35岁的时候失去童贞的那个人是别人介绍的。
set up with and and I
我
think part of why I think I might have
觉得我当时可能比较有
been attractive was because I was in
吸引力，部分原因是因为我当时参演了
like a number one movie at the time and
一部票房大卖的电影，
whatever and that guy was like an
等等。那个男生真是
awesome guy and I'd met him and I'd
太棒了。 我和那个男生见面了，我
waited so long at that point I really
等了很久，当时我真的
wanted to lose my virginity to someone
想把我的第一次献给一个
who I was really really into and I and I
我真正喜欢的人。我真的很喜欢他，
just I really like this guy I thought he
觉得他很
was so funny and cute and um and
有趣很可爱，而且
potentially like marriage material at
当时我觉得他很有潜力成为我的结婚对象。
the time I met him and so and so when I
所以，几年后我
did my year of Love experiment that was
做了“一年恋爱实验”，很
like a few years later so obviously I I
明显，
if I was still a virgin and going on all
如果我还是个处女，我肯定做不到，因为那时候
these dates because um at least I had
我已经有一些
some experience by that point but I
经验了。我
dated like 50 people in the one year in
在2019年那一年约会了大概50个人，就是为了积累一些经验，比如
like to find like cuz I just was behind
寻找真爱，因为我当时完全没有恋爱经验，从来
the eightball I'd never dated properly
没有真正谈过恋爱。
um so I needed to get some experience in
所以我需要在这方面积累一些经验，
that area and and legitimately trying to
并且真心实意地想要
find the one but um yeah it didn't
找到我的另一半。但是，嗯，结果并不
didn't quite work out you mentioned that
理想。你提到
you experimented with a zmek oh I did
你尝试过Zmek，哦，是的，
but I wish I'd known about it in 2020 it
但我希望我在2020年就知道它。
wasn't big then no I didn't even if I
当时并不怎么在意，真的，就算我
had known about it I would have tried it
知道有这种药，我也会
100% um but more for uh once I'd lost
百分百尝试。嗯，主要是因为我减掉了
like 35 kilos I was like I can't
35公斤之后，感觉自己没法
continue working out and having this
继续锻炼，也没法保持这种
level of focus like I can't and I was
专注力了，我
very worried that the weight would come
非常担心体重会反弹。现在，我又胖了
have gained back um 10 kilos or so
10公斤左右，可能是
because of um I guess having a baby I I
因为生了孩子吧。我
just can't work out in the level that I
没法像以前那样锻炼了。
used to and then I directed a movie
而且我还执导了一部电影，
all day long and being stress still
整天都要坐在椅子上，压力很大，现在还在恢复期。等
control when I'm you know not working 7
我不用一周工作七天的时候，压力应该就能控制住了。
days a week um uh and so I've tried it
所以，我试了
for a few months for like weight
几个月，想着大概是为了控制体重吧。
it um I definitely noticed that it it
我确实注意到它有效果，让
did I have like an unlimited ability to
我可以无限量地
eat sweets and chocolate and ice cream
吃甜食、巧克力、冰淇淋
and stuff and that drug helped um for me
之类的东西。这种药让我
not to feel full MH whereas I wouldn't
感觉不到饱，而以前我吃完之后……
feel like that before I would just could
以前我能吃
eat a ton of it like you know um so so I
很多，你知道，嗯，所以，我
actually actually liked it but um yeah I
其实挺喜欢吃的。但是，嗯，我
know I think I actually think for people
知道，我觉得对于像
like me those drugs can be really
我这样的人来说，那些药可能真的
effective but obviously I'm not on it
有效。当然，我
right now but maybe if I you know
现在没吃，但如果
prescribed it by a doctor I'd go back on
医生给我开了药，我可能会重新开始吃。
it when you lose weight your resonance
当你减肥的时候，你
with your audience changes as well
和观众的共鸣也会改变，
because to I I think Adele spoke to it
因为我觉得阿黛尔
as well and when she lost a lot of
也说过类似的话。当她减肥很多的时候，确实遭到了一些负面
backlash yeah I mean I think there was
评价。是的，我觉得
some people going oh she won't be funny
有些人会说，哦，她以后就不好笑了。
anymore but then I had this movie come
但是，在我大学最后一年，我拍了一部电影，我在里面
out senior year play a cheerleader who
扮演一个
went into a coma and then wakes up 20
昏迷了20年的啦啦队长，然后醒了过来。
years later and uh that was my first big
那是我第一部真正意义上的
comedy and it got something like 89
喜剧，上映的前10天，全球就有大约8900万个
million unique Netflix accounts watch it
Netflix独立账户观看了这部电影，
which was huge huge huge number so I was
这是一个非常非常大的数字。所以我就想，
like oh well I think they're probably
哦，好吧，我觉得那些说
the people are wrong about that I won't
我以后不好笑的人可能是错了。
be funny anymore or but did they feel
但是，有些人会感到
let down people I think some people did
失望吗？我觉得有些人确实会。
it's like say if you're in a family and
比如说，如果你在一个家庭里，
your sibling makes a change for the
你的兄弟姐妹做出了改变，变得
better and then you feel like ah well it
更好了，然后你就会想，哎呀，这
makes me feel bad because I didn't make
让我感觉很糟糕，因为我没有做出
the change and it makes me feel not as
改变，这让我觉得
good about myself so therefore I'm going
自己很差劲，所以我就会
to hate them for for changing how dare
恨他们，恨他们怎么敢
they change how dare they try to rise
改变，怎么敢努力
above um and I think there is some
向上？我觉得这其中确实存在一些
attitude but then you think to those
偏见。但你转念一想，如果
like the John Candy way and you die of a
像约翰·坎迪那样，你就会死于
heart attack or you know something
心脏病，或者你知道，
you get some serious uh I mean my father
你得了什么重病，比如糖尿病并发症，这样才能让那些人高兴。我父亲就是
died of a heart attack with
死于
complications with diabetes so I was
糖尿病并发症，所以我当时就想，
route if I kept going and I was like
如果我继续这样下去，我也会走上糖尿病这条路。我就想，这样就能
well does that make those people happy
让那些人高兴吗？
what you just say as you are and be
你就这样
unhealthy and then you die prematurely
不健康地活着，然后过早地死去，
that's not a great outcome like what do
这不是一个好结果。
those people want but I think as a
那些人到底想要什么？但我认为，作为一名
comedian you have so many different
喜剧演员，你有很多不同的
things in your toolkit uh and mainly
技巧，尤其是
your personality and so even though it's
你的个性。所以，即使很
easy to go oh you have that physical
容易说“哦，你身体有
irregularity and that's why people love
缺陷，所以人们才喜欢你”，但其实不然。
there are so many other elements it's
还有很多其他因素，事情
not as simplistic as that and so I just
没那么简单，所以我只是
utilize slightly different things have
运用了一些略微不同的东西。
you noticed any change in the way that
你有没有注意到，
people book you professionally or or
人们在专业上安排你演出、或者
respond to you professional or the roles
对你的专业反应，或者
you're given based on your well now I do
你被分配的角色方面有什么变化？嗯，我现在演了
a lot more dramatic stuff I mean I'm
很多戏剧性的角色，当然，我
still obviously doing the comedy stuff I
仍然在演喜剧。
mean I've just directed a movie which is
我刚刚执导了一部电影，这对我来说是
a big huge new career step but yeah I've
职业生涯中一个巨大的新里程碑。是的，我还有
got a movie coming out the arm and the
一部电影即将
seahorse here in the UK which is totally
在英国上映，叫《手臂与海马》，这是一部非常
serious and I just played Lady Capulet
严肃的作品。我刚刚
in a film which is totally not what you
在一部电影里扮演了凯普莱特夫人，这完全出乎你的意料，我绝对不会演这种角色。这
awesome but it's kind of how I started
很棒，但这有点像我
my career doing Shakespeare and stuff um
职业生涯的起点——演莎士比亚之类的剧，在
before I was bigger and so it's kind of
我还没那么红的时候。所以
coming back now to to doing that kind of
现在我又开始做这类
thing but more I noticed um I mean now
事情了，但我注意到，
I'm kind of in the middle because I'm
我现在处于一种中间状态，因为我又
like I've gained back some weight it was
胖了一些。
so weird to be to be someone who walks
作为一个走在
around the world kind of feeling a bit
世界上的人，感觉自己有点像
invisible um attractiveness wise and
隐形人，这种感觉很奇怪，尤其是在外貌方面。
then suddenly I lost all this weight and
突然间我瘦了很多，也
got so much positive validation like it
得到了很多积极的肯定，简直
was insane like people would open doors
难以置信。比如有人会帮
for you or carry your groceries to the
我开门，帮我把买的东西搬到
car for you or offer to do something for
车上，或者主动提出帮我做点什么
you or whatever and I just it was so
等等。这种
weird to experience that and I've
经历真的太奇妙了。我
experienced both sides of the coin like
体验过两种截然不同的感觉：一种是
to be kind of being invisible in that
在这个
area and then to be visible and it was
领域里几乎隐形，另一种是成为焦点。那种
it was bizarre it was like the attention
关注感真的很奇怪，
and I was like oh is this what hot
我当时就想，哦，这就是那些长得好看的
people feel get all the time um and they
人一直感受到的吗？他们总是能
get this kind of positive bias in
得到社会的这种正面评价。
society all the time um and I got such
我减肥后也得到了
um from the press and from people like
媒体和人们的积极反馈，几乎
every single person would make some
每个人都会对此发表
comment about it and and it's hard not
评论。很难不被这种感觉所感染。
to fall into liking that and you know
你知道，
now I've just been too stressed being a
我现在作为
director that I've kind of gone off the
导演压力太大了，所以有点儿疏于关注
band Health bandwagon but you've got I
健康，但我会重新开始的。你
will get back on it 42 years old you
42岁了，
underwent IVF and you had your daughter
做了试管婴儿，生下了女儿
Roy um but it appears you're still a
罗伊。但你看起来仍然是个
workaholic you just said earlier about
工作狂，你刚才也提到了
working seven days a week I know I've
工作。 我知道我一周七天都在工作，
I've come off a 9mon marathon of seven
我刚刚结束了一场长达九个月的马拉松式工作，
days a week I did an action film um
一周七天，我拍了一部动作片，
called bride hard directed my movie The
叫《新娘硬汉》，我执导了自己的电影《
Deb written the book and yeah so I'm
黛比》，还写了这本书。所以，我马上要
about to have a holiday what are you
休假了，你为什么要休假呢？
doing it for um cuz you could you know
因为你知道，
you've got multiple houses all over the
你在世界各地有很多房子，
world you've got huge success you've
你取得了巨大的成功，你做到了，
you've you've done it rebel I know and I
叛逆者，我知道。我
and my love life there is a happy story
和我的爱情生活也有一个幸福的故事，献给
to everyone listening I I have an
所有正在收听的人。我有一个
amazing partner Ramona who's absolutely
很棒的伴侣拉莫娜，她绝对是
an incredible partner um and so that
一个了不起的伴侣。所以，这个
story had had a happy ending as well I
故事也有一个美好的结局。我
keep saying to people I'm going to
一直跟别人说我要
retire now you know and then they're
退休了，你知道吗？然后他们会说，是
like yeah you'll have like 2 days off
啊，你大概会休息两天，然后
and then you'll have some idea for a
你就会冒出一个
movie and then you'll want to do it um
电影的想法，然后你就想把它拍出来。
so I think I'm always that little girl
所以，我想我永远都是那个
who at the dog shows was like reaching
在狗展上伸手
into bins to collect the aluminum cans
去捡铝罐
to earn money because I felt like I
赚钱的小女孩，因为我觉得自己
didn't have anything cuz I didn't have
一无所有，因为我
any money and so so part of me is always
没钱。 所以，我的一部分总是
that I have just have this drive to earn
渴望
money um and and that that motivates me
赚钱，这激励着我。很
and it's weird like I achieve a goal
奇怪，我实现了一个目标，
like coming to America was just to be in
比如来美国只是为了参演
one Hollywood movie but then you achieve
一部好莱坞电影，但当你实现了这个目标，却又觉得不够，然后你
want you know and now like you know I'd
想要更多。你知道，现在，我
like to win an Oscar or you know um have
想赢得奥斯卡奖，或者达到
that level of success you know winning
那种程度的成功。我知道赢得
the Oscars is going to change Zill I
奥斯卡奖会改变我，但也许
know probably not probably like there's
不会。
a curse on some women that win the
有些女性赢得
Oscars uh then they sometimes their love
奥斯卡奖后似乎被诅咒了，她们的爱情
life crumbles and they they get no jobs
生活有时会崩溃，而且在
for 2 years when after they win the
赢得奥斯卡奖后的两年内都找不到工作。
Oscar sometimes it's like a curse see
这就像一个诅咒。
you didn't see that in the hallucination
你看，你在幻觉中没有看到
what happened after no I didn't see that
之后发生了什么。不，我没有看到，
I just saw winning and feeling great
我只看到了胜利和那种感觉。
about it I mean I definitely know I need
我的意思是，我当然知道我需要
a break over the summer and I will have
在夏天休息一下，好好
have fun times and I've learned how to
玩玩。我现在学会了如何
have fun now cuz before like in my 20s I
享受生活，因为在我20多岁的时候，我甚至都不
didn't even do that I wouldn't even go
会这样做，我甚至都不会去
on a holiday i' be like no I have to
度假。 我当时想，不，我必须
keep working hard are you are you
继续努力工作。你
concerned and I'm asking this really for
担心吗？我其实是在问
myself here because I think I am are you
自己，因为我觉得我的确担心。你担心以后回头看时会想，
later in life and go you know what I
你知道吗，我当时
didn't have my priorities in
没有分清轻重缓急？
order yeah maybe and so I think having
嗯，也许吧。所以，我觉得有了
my gorgeous daughter and looking at at
我可爱的女儿，看着
her she makes me want to like not work
她，我就想少工作
as much and I think I didn't know how
一些。我想我以前不知道
she was going to affect my life um and
她会如何影响我的生活。嗯，
then now just knowing how much joy it is
现在我知道和
just to be around her and it makes me
她在一起有多么快乐，这让我
think less about myself and more about
少想自己，多想
her and my family um and so from that
她和我的家人。嗯，所以从这个
level I want to um not not work as much
层面来说，我想少工作一些，
and I have to be a bit more selective
我必须更有选择性。
you one of the things that I
我
found I have to say awesome I'm just
发现
going to be honest with you in your book
你的书里有一点很棒，我必须实话实说，
was um well there's so many things I
嗯，有很多东西我都
love the pictures and the whole design
喜欢，比如图片，还有整
of the book and how you weave humor into
本书的设计，以及你如何将幽默融入到
what I consider to be pretty important
我认为非常重要的
lessons of life
人生哲理中。
but oh you're holding up the redacted
哦，你拿着那些被涂黑的
Pages pages that that just have black
页面，
lines through them which means that
上面只有黑线划掉的那些页面， 这意味着
you've basically removed those sections
你基本上已经删除了那些章节。
now you well I didn't remove them okay
嗯，我没删，是
the publisher the UK publisher did
英国的出版商删的，
because in the in the UK the laws are
因为在英国，关于
about instances in your life yeah and
你生活中某些事情的言论自由度，法律和这里不一样。是的，
being a qualified lawyer I know you know
作为一名合格的律师，我知道你很了解
all about defamation laws um and it's a
诽谤法。嗯，
bit um the the US is a bit more free
美国
speech in in terms of defamation laws
在诽谤法方面言论自由度更高一些，
and the UK and Australia have higher
而英国和澳大利亚的
standards this chapter is called Sasha
标准更高。这一章的标题是“萨莎·
Barone and other other now
拜伦和其他混蛋”。
obviously I'm just going to take your
显然，我接下来要听你的。嗯，
lead on this yeah but um this has been a
这件事闹得沸沸扬扬，
huge story and I saw on your Instagram
我在你的Instagram上看到了
some Instagram it's weird because the
一些相关内容。很奇怪，因为这
book is about my whole life you know and
本书讲述的是我的一生，
yet this particular chapter has gotten
然而这一章却引起了
the most attention I guess because I'm
最多的关注，我想是因为我
saying something negative about a male
说了些关于男
comedian Sasha Baron Cohen um and in it
喜剧演员萨莎·拜伦·科恩的负面评价。在这一章里，我
describing like the worst professional
描述了
experience of my career which was 10
我职业生涯中最糟糕的经历，那是
years ago now on a movie called Grimsby
十年前拍摄电影《格林斯比》时
and working with him and it was an
和他合作的那次
experience that left me
经历，让我
feeling humiliated and degraded as a
感到羞辱和人格贬低。
so that chapter I guess because he's
所以，我想，这一章…… 因为他
come out and uh denied it it became a a
出面否认了这件事，所以它成了个
big
大
story what can you say about that
新闻。关于那段经历，你能说说吗？
experience I can say why I wrote it um
我可以说说我为什么写这本书。至于
and purely why it's reductive is um
为什么说它过于简化，是
because it's the publisher that gets
因为出版社被
sued and obviously they they wouldn't
起诉了，他们显然不想被一个
who's quite litigious so so that's why
爱打官司的人告，所以
they did that but the story is pretty
他们才那样做。但这个故事其实已经广为人知了，
much out there um so you could easily
所以你很容易就能从
about in the book but I wanted to write
书中推断出我在说什么。但我还是想写出来，
it because uh my story is not one of um
因为我的故事和
assault and you know
你
um thing things in Hollywood mine is not
在好莱坞听到的那些可怕的性侵故事不一样。我的故事不是
that uh it's more
那种，更像是
just kind of a situation at work
工作中遇到的糟糕情况。如果换作
that the 44y old version of me would
44岁的我，我会直接
have left and would have said H screw
离开，说“去
you I'm out of here I'm you know got
你的，我走了，我有
enough self-esteem to leave and know
足够的自尊离开，我知道
this isn't a good situation for me and
这对我来说不是个好环境”。但当时
then back then I stayed in it and and I
我却留了下​​来，而且还重拍了那部
did re-shoot on on the film because I
电影。 我
didn't want to be seen as
不想被认为
unprofessional and this was before the
不专业，而且这发生在#MeToo
me to movement and even though I wasn't
运动之前。尽管我当时并没有受到
being treated great I just I thought oh
很好的对待，但我还是想，
well I have to be professional um and
好吧，我必须保持专业，
and I have to stay and and finish it uh
我必须留下来，完成它。当时的
and it was a complicated situation we
情况很复杂，我们
were both represented by the same agent
俩当时都由同一个经纪人代理，
at the time and um there are a few
而且还有一些其他的
things going on and and I guess I wrote
事情发生。我想我写
it so that people the more people talk
这篇文章是希望人们多谈论这类
about stuff like this hopefully the less
事情，这样这类事情
it happens and then also
发生的可能性就会降低。另外，
um just I think I held shame because I
我觉得我当时很羞愧，因为我
went along with it and it's such a fine
参与其中。喜剧
between comb what's comedy and what's
和
playing a character and then really
角色扮演之间的界限非常模糊，很容易越界，
crossing the line into personal
变成人身
humiliation um and I think on that
羞辱。我觉得在那个
project it did it did cross the line and
项目中，它确实越界了，我为自己
I felt shame that I actively went along
主动参与其中而感到羞愧。
with it and so I guess writing it is
所以我想，写这篇文章某种程度上是在
kind of releasing the emotions I was
释放我一直压抑的情绪。
holding on to for that and I have no
我没有什么
motivation I mean I write in the chapter
动机，我的意思是，我在那一章里写道，
it's not about canceling somebody it's
这不是为了抵制谁，
just about um it kind of goes to show
只是……这在某种程度上说明了
why my self worth wasn't um wasn't where
为什么我的自我价值感很低。 事情并没有发生在
where it should have been and I should
它应该在的地方，我当时应该为
have stood up for myself and that's
自己挺身而出，就是这样。
that's and now the 44y old version of me
现在，44岁的我
would uh handle things much much
会用
differently and it's just it was 10
截然不同的方式来处理这件事。毕竟那是10
years ago and it was hard to know what
年前的事了，
to do even though I'm a lawyer and I
即使我是一名律师，也不知道该怎么办。我当时也
made the complaints and did what I could
提出了投诉，尽了全力。
do at the time I now would act very
现在我会采取完全
differently this is your life story this
不同的做法。这是你的人生故事，这
is your Memoir of all the experiences
是你所有经历的回忆录。
you've had Rebel when you look back
叛逆者，当你回顾
through all of these pages and all of
所有这些篇章，回顾所有
these days and all of these sort of
这些日子，回顾
seasons of your life was there a hardest
你人生中的所有这些阶段时，有没有最艰难的
moment oh God there's been so many hard
时刻？哦，天哪，有太多艰难的时刻了。
hard moment I think well probably the
我想，
darkest point in my life was when I was
我人生中最黑暗的时刻大概是在我
about 13 and you know you hit puberty
13岁左右的时候，你知道，进入青春期，
and you feel all these emotions
你会感受到各种各样的情绪。
and I felt you know unlovable unworthy
我觉得自己不值得被爱，不配拥有美好的
my life wasn't going to be anything um
人生，我的生活毫无意义。
and I was just isolated we were living
我当时很孤立，我们住在
out in the bush at that that point where
灌木丛里，
we had like snakes come crawling on the
蛇会爬到我们家的
back porch and Bush rats and like I was
后廊上，还有丛林老鼠。 感觉我当时就像
just Liv like it just was such a dark
莉芙一样，那是一段非常黑暗的
time um and that was probably the hard
时期，嗯，那可能是最难熬的一段时光了。
next for Rebel what's well I'm still
接下来Rebel有什么计划？嗯，我还在
directing the movie because I've got all
执导这部电影，因为
the technical elements to do now so
现在所有的技术环节都完成了，这对我来说
that's a big new challenge and I've
是一个巨大的挑战。我
directed this very empowering musical
执导了一部非常励志的音乐剧，它非常非常
that's very very joyful and and very
欢乐，也非常
it's hilarious so I'm very proud of that
搞笑，所以我为此感到非常自豪。
um and then I think I don't know I still
嗯，然后，我想我仍然
have because that Vision was I won an
有一个愿景，那就是赢得
Oscar and I haven't won one so I'd like
奥斯卡奖，但我还没有得过，所以我很想拿一个。但是，
to do that but then you know I would
你知道，我更
just like to be more of a mom who has
想成为一个能
spends that quality time with her family
和家人共度美好时光的妈妈，是的，我就是
and is yeah is that kind of uh person
那种人，
and not so striving but I don't know I
而不是那么拼命。我不知道，我内心
always have this thing in me that I'm
一直有一种动力，我
very driven and working hard and just
很努力工作，一直都是
always had that but I would like to
这样，但我想
maybe let go of that if you were to um
也许可以放下这种动力。如果你回到
go back now to that 13-year-old Rebel
13岁，回到那个正在
that was going through all of those sort
经历各种心理
of challenges in her mind and you could
挑战的Rebel，你会对
tell something say something to her that
她说些什么，让
would better equipped her
她更好地应对未来的挑战？
to um for the next sort of 20 years to
接下来的二十年左右，
come because there's going to be lots of
会有很多
you know young women that are struggling
年轻女性
with all the things you described and
和
young men oh yeah and I know what it's
年轻男性像你描述的那样挣扎。我知道那种感觉，
like to feel invisible to be so lonely
感觉自己像个隐形人，孤独寂寞，与世隔绝，感觉自己一无是处。我以前也挺
pretty average I mean I was smart I
普通的，我
always had being smart but like it's
一直都很聪明，但就是很
average no one really looked twice or
普通，没人会多看
thought twice about me and and and I
我一眼，也没人会多想我。我
know what it's like but it's if you want
知道那种感觉，但如果你下定
to be determined and you want to change
决心，想要改变
your life like you can and you don't
自己的人生，你就能做到，你不必
have to stay in that situation like you
继续待在那种境地。你
can actively do things to make your life
可以积极主动地去改善生活，
better and to make it more how you want
让它更符合你的心意。
and I mean at the time I just had to
当时我只能
tell myself that there was nobody around
告诉自己，身边没有人能
to to tell me that but to those young
告诉我这些。但我想对那些年轻人说，
um you you can like you can actively
你们可以，你们可以积极主动地去改变。
the creative arts because which can be
创意艺术就是一个很好的选择，它涵盖了
so many different things like writing or
很多方面，比如写作、
painting or uh not not just acting and
绘画，或者，不仅仅是表演和
being on a stage all those things cuz
舞台演出等等。
you might not know what your voice is or
你可能不知道…… 你的声音，或者说你
how to express yourself and those kind
如何表达自己，这些
of areas are so important because it can
方面都非常重要，因为它们能
help you find your voice MH um and so I
帮助你找到自己的声音。所以我想鼓励
you to go into that those kind of
你去追求这些，
Pursuits even if it's just something you
即使只是
do in your bedroom with a notebook and
在卧室里用笔记本
you're writing song lyrics or you're
写歌词，或者
yeah writing a diary or something um
写日记什么的。
that form of creative expression can be
这种形式的创造性表达真的非常
really really useful and you're the
有用，而你就是
prime example of that in many respects
很多方面的最佳例证。
you went from being that extremely shy
你从一个极其害羞的
individual to the point as you say that
人，正如你所说，害羞到
people thought it was some kind of
人们认为你患有某种
social disorder um to being a Hollywood
社交障碍，到成为好莱坞
Mega star you also went in the personal
巨星。在个人生活
context you went from being someone who
方面，你从一个
lost their virginity at 35 years old and
35岁才失去童贞、单身、
wasn't in a relationship and was very
明显
sort of clearly avoidant yeah to being
回避型人格的人，变成了现在这样——
which I do slightly regret now like I
我现在有点后悔，我当时想，
was like oh maybe but then yeah I again
哦，也许吧。但我仍然
I do believe that I wouldn't have the
相信，
career that I had if I'd focused more on
如果我之前更注重
relationships and and health before that
人际关系和健康，我就不会有今天的成就。
there's a lot of people out there that
很多人正在经历这样的转变。
are arriving maybe in their late 30s and
到了三十多岁，他们
that maybe have hear that clock ticking
或许会感觉到时间在流逝，
yeah and then they reflect on the
然后他们会反思
decisions they've made over the last 20
过去二十年做出的决定，然后
years and they say you know what
说：“你知道吗，
actually I hear the clock ticking and I
我其实感觉到了时间的流逝，我
do want a family a lot of people also
想要一个家庭。”很多人也会
say I hear the clock ticking I don't
说“我感觉到了时间的流逝”，
some people just don't hear the clock
有些人则完全没有这种感觉。
ticking at all yeah um but there's a lot
嗯，但确实有很多
of people that are arriving at that age
人到了这个年纪会想：“好吧，
hindsight now maybe I maybe I got
现在回想起来，我之前的那些优先事项，也许我以前做错了。”
something wrong here earlier and it's
这
difficult and I think that's really what
很难。我认为
your your book does so well is it's so
你的书之所以如此出色，正是因为它非常
honest about that sort of internal
坦诚地展现了
conversation you had with yourself about
你与自己进行的这种内心对话：
made if I want to achieve something else
如果我想实现其他目标，就必须做出改变；
and I've decided I want something else
我已经决定要追求其他的东西。
and throughout your whole story it's so
在你的整个故事中，你都
clear that you can change yeah and it's
清楚地表明，你可以改变，而且
never too late to change and it's yeah
改变永远不晚。是的，
and I really if anybody listening is
如果听众中有人像我一样属于
like a late bloomer like like me I mean
大器晚成，
I don't think there's any shame in that
我认为这没什么可耻的。
and that's one of the reasons why I put
我之所以把
that virginity story in the book because
初夜的故事写进书里，
like on the one hand it's very
一方面是因为
embarrassing for me to say that but then
说出来让我很尴尬，但另一方面，
if that helps other people out there
如果这能帮助其他人，让他们觉得“
feel like oh you know okay well Rebel
哦，你知道吗，好吧，Rebel以前也是这样，
was like that and look at the life she
看看她
has now and um so I would want them to
现在的生活”，那我就希望他们
not feel embarrassed about that because
不要为此感到尴尬，因为
doesn't really matter when you Bloom
绽放的时间真的不重要，
like what age or um you know things have
比如多大年纪，或者你知道，有些事情发生在
come to me later in life but I think all
我人生后期，但我认为
that matters is that it it has come to
重要的是它最终发生在了
me um now why am I saying the word come
我身上。嗯，我为什么老是说“发生”这个词，
so much talkity I don't know um but I
我也不知道，嗯，
yeah I just I'm glad that my life turned
我只是很高兴我的人生最终是这样的结果，
out you know I didn't get all these
你知道，我没有在20多岁的时候就拥有所有这些
awesome things in my 20s it it happened
美好的事物，它们发生在
later and um and and that's okay we have
之后，嗯，这没关系。我们
a closing tradition on this podcast
这个播客有个结尾的传统，上
where the last guest leaves a question
一位嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留一个问题，但
for the next guest not knowing who
不知道是谁。这次
and the question that's been left for
留给MH的问题
is those people that you love the most
是：你最爱的人，
what is preventing you from spending
是什么阻止你花
enough time hugging them are you able to
足够的时间陪伴他们？ 拥抱他们，你能改变
this okay so what's so the people I love
这种情况吗？好吧，我最爱的人，
the most obviously apart from my family
除了我的家人之外，当然
family is my daughter and my partner and
就是我的女儿和我的伴侣了。
what's preventing me from hugging them
阻止我拥抱他们的
the most is literally physically not
最大原因，就是我无法和
being with them because I'm like out out
他们在一起，因为我忙于
promoting the book and um uh or if I'm
宣传新书，或者如果我在
shooting something and it's not
拍摄一些不
appropriate for the baby to come um so
适合孩子出门的戏份，或者我
so not physically being in the same
无法和
country or or city as them because I'm
他们身处同一个国家或城市，因为我
working too much and it says are you
工作太忙了。问题问我，你
able to change this and I and I am able
能改变这种情况吗？我能改变，方法是
to change it by uh not just
不要
accepting too much work
接受太多的工作，
and um you know prioritizing the family
而是把家庭放在首位。Rebel，
more Rebel your book is incredible it's
你的书太棒了，它之所以
incredible for so many reasons because
棒，有很多原因，因为
it seeks to answer those really critical
它试图回答那些
questions that I think a lot of people
我认为很多人都在苦苦挣扎的关键问题，比如
romance it's about fertility it's about
爱情、生育、
am I good enough it's about finding love
我是否足够好、寻找真爱等等。
it's about it's an honest reflection of
它真实地反映了
what I think a lot of Workaholics go
我认为很多现代工作狂的经历。 书中
weaving in a story which I don't think
穿插着一个
many people know about your early
鲜为人知的故事，关于你的
childhood and where you've really come
童年早期，你的真实出身，
from and all the odds you've had to
以及你为了走到今天这一步所克服的重重困难——从
fight against coming from where you've
你的
come from to get to where you ended up
出身到如今的成就，你真的非常了不起。
word but you confront the trade-offs
但你也直面了
which a lot of people don't always talk
很多人不愿提及的取舍，
about those trade-offs we all have to
这些取舍我们每个人都必须面对。
make because as you said in this
正如你在刚才的
conversation you can't have it all in
谈话中所说，人生不可能拥有一切，
life and so you know you can't have it
所以你知道你不可能
all at the same time yeah for sure you
同时拥有所有。当然，你
can probably have it all just not at the
或许可以拥有所有，只是不能
same time yes anything yeah and life
同时拥有。是的，任何事情都是如此。生活
just presents these tra especially for
总是充满这些挑战，尤其是对于那些
people that are anomalies they have to
与众不同的人来说，他们必须
make even bigger trade-offs than others
做出比其他人更大的取舍。
it's a remarkably funny book um in such
这是一本非常有趣的书，以一种非常巧妙、毫不费力的
a subtle untry hard way which is 100%
方式呈现，这一点毋庸置疑。
but even you in conversation are the
就像你在谈话中
same you're funny without even trying
一样，你毫不费力地就很有趣，这很了不起。《
which is remarkable and the almond and
杏仁与
the Sea Horse I I was told it was coming
海马》我听说将于
out on the 10th of May yeah in cinemas
5月10日在英国的电影院上映。
here in the UK yeah so it's out now and
现在已经上映了，
everyone can go and watch it yeah um and
大家都可以去看，嗯，这部
very serious uh movie and that was where
电影讲的是创伤性脑损伤，非常严肃。
I kissed my first woman in that movie
我在那部电影里献出了我的初吻，
The French actress Charlotte gainsburg
法国女演员夏洛特·甘斯伯格，
and the rest is history yeah that's yeah
剩下的故事你们都知道了。是的，那是
part of my big part of my life on screen
我人生中非常重要的银幕篇章。《
Rebel thank you thank you stepen I
叛逆者》，谢谢你，斯蒂芬，我
really appreciate it and it is my most
真的很感激。这是我最
vulnerable intimate thoughts put out
脆弱、最私密的想法，我把它公之于众。嗯，即使
there um but yeah even if like 10 people
只有十个人能
relate to it and get something positive
感同身受，从中获得一些积极的东西，那对
world to me and um so even why it's
我来说也意义非凡。所以，虽然这
nerve-wracking having the book out there
本书出版让我很紧张，但
it's it's awesome at the same time
同时也很棒。
[Music]
[音乐]